翻译校正润色：TG2G BOSS  特别鸣谢：安俊 车干
We were once a peaceful race of intelligent mechanical beings.
我们本是一群曾经热爱和平的超机械生命体
But then came the war.
但是后来爆发了战争
Between the autobots who fought for freedom,
其中汽车人为自由而战
..and the decepticons who dreamt of tyranny.
而霸天虎为欲望而战
Over matched,and out numbered.
与敌人数量上差距悬殊，
Our defeat was all but certain.
我们的失败似乎不可避免
But in the wars final days.
在战争的最后阶段
One autobot ship escaped the battle.
一艘汽车人的飞船逃离了战场
It was carrying a secret cargo.
它带着一批神秘的货物
Which would have changed our planets fate.
足以改变我们星球命运的东西
A desperate mission.
这个几乎不可能完成的使命
Our final hope.
是我们最后的希望。
A hope,that vanished.
然而希望最终破灭了...
VLA Radio Observatory - New Mexico,1961
1961年，新墨西哥VLA天文台
Move it there.
一个在这
Move it there,one more down there.
另一个在那 ，还有更多的
you see
看到了么?
Capture contacted.
检测到了碰撞
We have impact confirmed.
我们已经确认了
Contacted.
月球发生碰撞
- 22:50 GMT. - What? NASA DIRECTOR - LANGLEY,VIRGINIA
什么？(美国航空航天局主任)
Give me SEC-DEV on the phone right away.
帮我连线国防部长
五角大楼 - 国家防御司令部
Mr. McNamara,the President is expecting you.
McNamara先生，总统在等你
- Get Bobby in here. - Mr. President
到这来Bobby  -总统先生
Designation,top secret.
这是顶级机密
We believe a UFO has crashed into the moon.
我们确认有UFO在月球上坠毁
We think the Russians are on to it as well.
我们也相信苏联人同样发现了
Well then you tell NASA to move heaven and earth.
通知宇航局，抓紧登月计划
We need to get to the moon.
我们需要到月球
We're going to attempt a manned mission.
我们正在尝试载人任务
NASA said it would take five years.
宇航局说，准备载人飞行任务还需要准备5年
You get there before the Russians.
你们必须赶在苏联人前面
I believe that this nation should commit itself.
我相信目前我们致力于此
To achieving the goal.
我们民族的首要目标
- Fifteen seconds. - Before this decade is out.
-55秒  -就是在这10年里
Of landing a man on the moon.
派人登月
And returning him safely to the earth.
并且安全返回
Ignition sequence starts
发射倒计时启动
Five...Four....three...
5...4...3....
two...one.
2...1...
And ignition.
点火发射
Lift off,we have a lift off.
升空，我们升空了
Thirty two minutes past the hour.
过去1小时32分钟
Lift off on Apollo 11,tower three.
“阿波罗11号”在第三塔架升空
Apollo 11 is on the way.
“阿波罗11号”正在朝着目标运行
Riding that pillar of flame from the Saturn five.
驾乘着着它无比耀眼辉煌的尾焰
Out there 400,000 miles away.
向着40万公里的距离外前行
Where the moon is waiting for man's first arrival.
月球正在等待人类的第一次造访
Houston you're a go for landing,over.
休斯顿，已经准备好登陆 完毕
40 feet,down 2 1/2. Picking up some dust.
距离13公尺 从表面上看都是土
Thirty feet,two and a half down.
距离10公尺 下了一半
Four Forward. Drifting to the right a little.
已经能看到我们的影子了
20 feet,down a half.
20英尺 下了一半
Contact light.
请求着落
Okay,engine stop.
批准 关闭引擎
Houston,tranquility base here,The Eagle has landed.
休斯顿基地 小鹰号已经安全降落
You got a bunch of guys about to turn blue. We're breathing again.
刚才真的很紧张 现在终于可以放下心了
Perhaps 400 million persons are watching this broadcast today.
大概有四亿人目睹了这一历史性的时刻
Of the greatest event in our time.
在这充满意义的时刻
And one of the great events of all recorded history.
人类历史上最伟大的一刻
I'm at the foot of the ladder.
我正在走下楼梯
I'm going to step on to land now.
现在我踏上月球表面了
That's one small step for man,
这是我个人的一小步
one giant leap for mankind.
却是人类的一大步
- Are we good? - Yes sir.
-准备好了吧  -是的，长官
Unofficial time on the first step 1092....
转到1092 非正式频道...
Eagle we're getting a signal interference.
小鹰号 我们失去信号...
Do you copy?
你能听到我们吗
We now have a confirmation. Loss of signal from Apollo 11.
刚收到消息，我们与“阿波罗11号”失去了联系
阿波罗11号 这里是休士顿 完毕
The Apollo 11 is for the moment,on the far side of the moon.
“阿波罗11号”现在是位于月球另一面
Neil,you are dark on the rock.
尼尔，你的连接被中断了
Mission is a go.
继续执行任务
You have 21 minutes.
你有21分钟的时间
Please stand by,18-45 seconds and counting.
要蛋定，你有13分45秒时间...
My god.
额滴神啊
It's some sort of giant metal face.
这看上去就像一个巨大的金属脸
Jesus.
耶稣
Control,we are inside the ship.
控制中心 我们进到了太空船里面
Extensive damage.
损害很严重
Way to big to check the entire ship.
太大了 我们没办法仔细搜索
Everything is dead in here,Houston.
所有东西都死了 休士顿
No signs of life anywhere.
这里没有任何生命迹象
This things a mess.
这里一团糟
We copy.
收到
You got seven minutes on your oxygen.
你们的氧气供应还有7分钟
We are not alone after all,are we.
在宇宙中我们并不孤单，是吗？
No,sir.
是的 长官
We're not alone.
我们并不孤单
All right,go ahead Mr. President.
您好，总统先生
Hello,Neil,Buzz.
你好 尼尔和巴斯
I'm talking to you by telephone from the oval room at the White House.
我在白宫办公室用电话跟你们通话
And this certainly has to be the most historic telephone call ever made.
这无疑是一段将要载入史册的通话
I just can't tell  you how proud we all are.
我无法描述你们的成就让我感到多么的自豪
For every American,this has to be the proudest day of our lives.
对于每一个美国人这是他们一生中最值得骄傲的一天
Because of what you have done
因为你们的成功
We have splashed down.
我们已经降落
The heavens has become a part of man's world.
使宇宙也已经成为人类世界的一部分
For one priceless moment.
在这最珍贵的一刻
In all of history of man.
在人类的历史上
All the people on this earth are truly one.
全世界的人都已融合为一体
Along with their pride in which you have done.
他们对你们的成功感到骄傲
You've inspired us to redouble our efforts,
并激励我们加倍努力
to bring peace and tranquility to Earth.
带来和平 祈望你们安返地球
My hero,
needs to wake up.
我的大英雄 该起床了
What is that?
那是什么？
This is your new lucky bunny.
这是你的新幸运兔子
Yeah, it's a beautiful thought, Carly.
是啊，这可真漂亮， Carly
But I don't think it's the whole, uh, bunny that's lucky.
但我不认为兔子的幸运是整只
You see it's just this section here.
你看，它只是在这个部份
You see it's just the rabbit's foot that's lucky.
只有兔子的脚是幸运的
All right, it's just a good luck charm.
这是一个好运气的护身符
Hmm, help you think positive.
它会帮助你积极思考
Today's important.
今天是很重要的
Come on, get up.
来吧 起床吧
- Hey, wear that nice tie.- Yeah.
- 嘿 系这条漂亮的领带 - 好啊
You need any money for lunch?
您需要午餐钱吗
No, I don't need any money for lunch.
不 我不需要午餐钱
I have money from yesterday's lunch.
我还有昨天的午餐钱
You love it, don't you.
你喜欢我对不对
I'm just your American boy-toy.
我只是你的玩具
A lover boy-toy.
一个可爱的玩具
You how demoralizing it is to save the world twice,
令人泄气的是我拯救了地球2次
to be groveling for a job.
却找不到一份工作
They don't know you saved the world, Sam.
人们并不知道你拯救了世界 Sam
I mean I do, I believe you.
我是说只有我知道 我相信你
If everyone knows, I could get a job right here in D.C.
如果每个人都知道，我就可以在华盛顿找到一份工作了
I mean I should be working with the autobots.
我是说我应该与汽车人在一起
Otherwise, it's not fair.
不然这不公平
Come on, they paid for your college.
得了吧 他们付你大学的学费
The president gave you a hero medal.
总统还给了你一个英雄奖章
Thank you, man. Great job.
谢谢你 Sam 干得漂亮
- Wow.- And as I recall that wasn't even the highlight of your day.
- 哇 - 我记得你在那一天还发生了什么事
- Mr. Ambassador, here. - British embassy you're up next.
- 大使先生 在这里 - 下一位是英国大使
- It's not really.. I couldn't even if I wanted to. - Leave it there.
- 这不是真的...我不能 即使我想 - 放在那里
Leave it in the box, right.
放在盒子里 对了
You keep it in there, what a gorgeous box.
放在那里 多漂亮一个盒子啊
Oh yeah, my medal.
噢 我的奖章
You know who gave that to me?
你知道我是谁给的？
Who?
谁？
- POTUS. - Oh.
- 听好了 - 是―
The president of the United States.
美国总统
Hey, it's hard for everybody to get a job.
嘿 可现实是工作还是很难找
I don't have time. You see my parents are going to be here in a week.
我没有时间了 我爸妈这星期就要来了
From their road-trip party world tour.
在他们的世界巡回之旅后
My dad gets here, and I don't have a job.
我爸来了要是知道我还没有找到工作
He's gonna spank me you know. It's go time for me.
你知道，一定给我一巴掌 我就得走人了
All  right, tonight I'll give you a job.
好吧 今晚我给你一份工作
Romance me with a nice dinner and, uh...
先跟我来个浪漫的晚餐 然后 嗯...
maybe get that banish.
也许可以得到相对的奖励
Ohh
喔
- Good looking.- Get out of here.
- 真好看 - 快滚出去
Wait, no, no, no, no, no.
等等 不 不 不 不 不
Oh, he's gross.
哦，他发飙了
She's good.
她很赞
They've been stranded here. Somebody's got to watch out...
有人一直待在这里偷窥...
- ...for them,  you know. - Yesterday that one was in my underwear drawer.
- 总是这样，你知道的 - 昨天还有一个躲在我的内衣抽屉里
Good reason, it looked real good too.
好借口 它看起来真的不赖
- What are you hitting, huh? - I want a normal boyfriend.
- 你为什么打我 - 我只想要一个正常的男友
- That's what you love about me, isn't it. - Heh, what a cry baby.
- 这就是你为什么爱我 不是吗 - 嘿，哭什么，宝贝
You know I don't have the word yet.
你知道我可没这么说过
Maybe a little bit closer when you can pay your half of the rent.
也许当你可以付你的一半租金时 我们就可以更亲密一点点
Bye.
再见
Frinking shorting my circuits out here.
憋死我了 电路都短路了
It's inhumane, what it is.
这是不人道的 搞什么
Make us live in a box on a balcony.
在你的阳台这么一个破地方过日子
Right next to a beast.
跟一只野兽
- Like a common animal. - Stop, okay.
- 和一只低智商的动物 - 闭嘴 好吗
You and your creepy sidekick, you can't be in here without permission.
你和你那恶心的哥们 都不许随便进到我的地盘
According to who, Miss blondy-blonde?
谁说的 那个金头发的娘们
Get out little doggie.
走吧 你这只笨狗
Hah!
哈！
Yo brain's what's up?
你怎么样啊 伙计
Doing good.
还行
Ah shoot, I'd seen this one.
哎呀 我想我看过这个剧情
It's the one where Spock goes nuts.
是个令人疯狂着迷的故事
You know Sam, I don't know about moving in with this chick.
知道么Sam，我不知道我们是否应该适应有这个女孩的生活
Uh, what if she dumps us like the last girl?
嗯 如果她像上个女孩让我们失望
What she was mean, didn't like her.
提她干什么 我不喜欢她
Us guys got to stick together.
我们男人必须站在同一阵线
我们 我们是一家人
No, we're not family. You're a political refuge.
不 我们不是一家人 你们只是来我这避难
And I have finally found someone who appreciates me for me.
我有我自己的家人
Well you tell her that we're not your pets.
那你跟她说 我们不是你宠物
And we're not your toys.
更不是你的玩具
All right, we're an advanced genius alien race,
好吧 我们是先进的外星智能种族
...just looking for a home.
只想寻求一个新的家
-  We could leave it right here. - Didn't think we should stop.
- 我们得马上离开这 - 我们是不是应该适可而止了
Come on what are they going to do, tow it?
拜托 你想怎么做 拖走它？
Where is he?
他在哪儿？
Sammy!
Sam
- Oh, come on now Sammy, ha, ha. - Sam.
- 哦 拜托 过来吧 Sam 哈 哈 - Sam
I miss you guys so much.
我非常想念你们
Sure you did, what do you think?
是啊 你觉得呢
- Look at that. - Cute.
- 看那个 - 真可爱
- Stop it. - Wait until you see the end..
- 等等 - 期待看到结果...
Oh I love your little tie. Hey, where's my girl?
我爱死你的小领带了 嘿 我的女孩呢
- Where's my girl, where's my beautiful Carly? - She at work, Ma.
- 我漂亮的Carly呢？  -她上班去了，妈
- She's got a new job. - Right.
- 她找了一份新工作 - 好啊
I thought you were going to be here in a week.
我还以为你们一星期后才到
The 21st of the 11th, Dad remember?
21号 而不是11号 爸爸还记得吗
- It's all ..... - .. A love job with flies.
- 我们已经溜达好几圈了 - 正确说我们早过来好几天了
Oh, are we keeping you from something?
我们可以说说别的
Like say, your job.
譬如你的新工作好吗
Well it's about time.
差不多了
You had us worried.
别担心
Uh, I have, uh, job interviews.
嗯 我 嗯 正要去面试
Oh, that's good.
哦 这很好
- Well that sucks. - Stop it.
- 好个屁 - 闭嘴
You don't have to be so negative Dad, you know.
你们不必如此消极
You're in DC, you're here with your son, your family.
你们在华盛顿 有儿子 家庭
- I mean it's good times. - Except it sucks that you don have a job.
- 可以好好享受人生 - 这么说你一直都没找到工作
- Good things to do here too, right? - Yeah.
- 还有很多地方可以逛 对吗 - 是啊
Right, museums and monuments, okay.
对啊 博物馆和纪念碑什么的
- I'll see you tonight. - I'm bagging the kid.
- 今晚再见 - 我已经整装待发了
Sam, I think for an interview you should wear real pants.
Sam 我觉得你面试应该穿正式点的裤子
I think in life you should wear real pants.
我认为在生活中你应该穿真正的裤子
Oh, wha...what happened to Bumble Bee?
哦 怎么...大黄蜂发生什么事了
He's off on his missions, I had to get this as a back-up.
他有任务 所以我换了一辆车
Oh, your car has a job, huh?
哦 你的车都上班了，是吧？
What does it change into?
那么大黄蜂换新造形了？
It doesn't change into anything.
没有，他没变什么
It's a collectors item, I got if for a steal.
这辆是我从古董店找的
It just needs some work, trust me.
只需要稍微修修 相信我
Oh, I think it's darling. It reminds me a lot of Bumble Bee.
哦，我认为这不错 这让我想起了以前的大黄蜂
If Bumble Bee were a sad piece of shit.
那个曾经的破烂货大黄蜂
Come on we'll give you a ride.
来吧，还是我们载你一程
In the years since our arrival.
自从这几年我们来到
Our new home, Earth had seen much change.
我们的新家园-地球， 一切都改变了
Energon detectors guard its cities now.
高科技的监视器开始监测 守卫着城市
Long range defense systems watch the skies.
远距离防御系统则防护着太空
MIDDLE EAST - ILLEGAL NUCLEAR SITE
- So now we assist our allies.
所以我们帮助我们的盟友－人类
In solving human conflicts.
解决他们之间的冲突
To prevent mankind from bringing harm to itself.
避免人类互相残杀
The Defense Minister's car.
国防部长的汽车
让他们通过
On the ground. Better not move, and stay there.
通通把武器扔掉 呆在那里别动
We work in secret teams on various missions around the globe.
我们在全球各地执行秘密任务
And all the while, we search for signs.
同时也始终在寻找迹象
Of our true enemies return.
证明我们真正的敌人要回来了
I am Voshkod, general council with Ukrainian department of energy.
我是沃什库克 乌克兰的能源部的主管
My government will officially deny that we're having this conversation.
我国政府正式否认 我们曾进行了这次的谈话
At one of our decontamination facilities a discovery was made.
在我们废弃的设施里发现
Which I fear may be alien in nature.
疑似外星人的能源
The Facility's name is, Chernobyl.
地点是切尔诺贝利
Mr. Voshkod.
沃什库克先生
Uninhabited since '86.
自1986年以来 这里就被废弃
I hear it won't be livable again for another 20,000 years.
而且听说2万年也不会恢复
At least. The Ukraine was the most fertile land, it's a tragedy.
是啊 这里曾是全乌克兰最肥沃的土地 真是悲剧
This way.
往这边来
Gear up, we have 60 minutes on the ground. Watch your radiation levels.
检查装备 我们有60分钟查找辐射源
Mr. Voshkod, where's your protective gear?
沃什库克先生 你的防护装备呢
Where's your protective gear?
你不用防护装备
It would not matter.
没有关系
For me it's only matter of time.
对我来说这都是小事
Through the school.
这原来是所学校
Uri will take you below. And one other thing, Colonel.
尤里会带你下去 还一件事情 上校
In private, there was some military experi...
私下的 还有些能源的实验...
It can wait.
还是等等吧
Keep moving, stay tight.
继续前进 跟紧
Okay, right here. Bring up the light.
这里 我们找到了，借光
Officer, we got a visual.
长官 我们找到了
We've found an object. Strapped in some kind of metal harness.
看上去只是一个金属线圈
What's this?
这是什么？
Guys, (Garbled)
天呐，为什么会有苏联太空计划标志的东西
- Sputnik. - Energon readings, sir.
- 人造卫星 - 数据探测读取中 长官
It's strong.
很强大
Below us.
就在我们下面
It's coming fast.
它在快速接近...
Go there, go there.
快跑 快跑
Get to top, now.
到上面去 快点
Let's go, let's go!
快点 快点
Let's go its an autobot.
我们走，这是汽车人
Stay behind me.
躲到我后面
Move, move!
快 快
Optimus!
擎天柱
Fall back!
撤退
Bring it flank, bring it flank come on.
带到侧面 到侧面来 快点
Get the heavy weapons.
重型武器
Optimus.
擎天柱！
该死！
What the hell was that thing?
这他妈是谁
That is Shockwave.
这就是震荡波
Why was he after this?
他想要这个
It's impossible.
这怎么可能
This is an engine part.
这是我们星球飞船引擎的一部分
From a long lost Autobot ship.
很久以前坠毁的汽车人飞船
Pleasure working with you.
很高兴和你一起工作
Interviews this is so exciting.
采访是如此令人兴奋
Honey, do you want some gum?
亲爱的 来块口香糖吧
Your breath gets really gnarly when you're nervous.
当你紧张时嘴巴会有口臭的
Mr. Whit-wickey.
维特维奇先生
Yep, the search is over.
是的 在这里
I'm Mr. Whitley.
我叫维特利
- Is any one else joining? - No.
- 还有别人要来吗？ - 没有
No?
没有
- Want me to move right there, I'm okay. - I prefer not.
- 那要我往那边坐坐吗 - 没有这必要
Sensei.
森塞
Ready, begin.
准备 开始
Uh, graduated this year majored in geo politics, minor text things.
嗯，我今年毕业于普林斯顿 主修地缘政治学 副修文书
Very interested in government technologies.
我对政府科技技术很感兴趣
As they intersect and co-exist.
当他们相交和并存
Shape, future.
创造未来
Why did we bother sending him to an ivy college for?
为什么我们要送他到大学名校
Three months out of school and he can't find a job.
毕业三个月还找不到工作
-Mr. Matsu-piece-u. - Mr. Matsu
- 松井先生 - 松本
- Masi.........Moto - Masu Moto.
- 玛斯....摩托 - 马苏摩托车
- Martha, can I call you Martha? - No you may not.
- 玛莎 我可以叫你玛莎吗 - 不 你不行
Okay. Jack, there's two type of people in this world.
好了，世界上有这么几类人
There's thinkers and there's doers.
有思想家和实干家
There's winners, there's dreamers and there's buds.
有赢家、还有梦想家和空想主义者
What about, some witnesses.
对于这些人，你有什么看法
You have a very trustworthy face.
你有张值得信赖的脸
You remind of like a...an Asian Colonel Sanders.
就像亚洲的先知山达士
A man I can trust.
一个可以信任的人
It's a millennial, you know like some kind of lost generation.
八零后，你知道可真是迷惘的一代人
Why was the FBI looking for you?
为什么联邦调查局找你
The what?
什么
Yeah, FBI getting a flag there.
是啊 这有联邦调查局得到的资料
Did you ever have any craziness when you were fourteen.
说你十四岁时曾经发过神经疯
They were very kind to me, found me in a jiffy.
他们对我很好，瞬间就找到我
Uh, and that's all been expunged.
嗯 这些都被删除掉了
Wound up getting a medal, actually.
其实那时奥巴马还给了我奖章
Just saying. It's always good to have a medal guy in the office, with a medal.
他们说在办公室里放个奖章是件不错的事
- From Obama? - Yeah.
- 奥巴马给你的？ - 是啊
In this office, we're mostly republicans.
可我们这里主要都是共和党人
Soo.
所以...
- I'm not feeling to good. - No.
- 感觉不太舒服 - 不舒服
- No. - Why don't you get a little dipping tray.
- 是的 - 你为什么不拿个碗
And dip the dog in the pepto, that's the solution.
把热狗泡在里面 不就搞定了
Pow, I got another one, we gotta go, come on.
不错，我还有一个面试，得走了 快点
Really?
真的吗
Sit.
坐下
Got a nice cell from this.
好好表现
Sam Witwicky, recent college graduate.
Sam 维特维奇先生 刚刚大学毕业
Previous experience next to zero.
工作经验为零
Yet, he has a recommend letter from our board.
然而 他有张我们董事会的推荐信
W.T.F. to that.
W.T.F.这个
Do I know somebody on your board?
你们董事会里有人认识我
Here's the deal, we know who we are.
这里不靠关系 我们知道我们是谁
Accuretta systems is called the leader in telecom.
Accuretta系统被称为电信业的领导者
Aerospace, 17 billion in profit last year.
航空事业局 去年盈利17亿元
We contract for DOP, NASA, JPL you name it.
我们与DOP NASA JPL都有业务
You can find here doors open for you.
你在这里意味着一切大门为你敞开
And what, first job out of college is critical, Kid.
毕业后的第一份工作很重要 年轻人
You either take a step down the correct career path.
他会让你走上正确的职业生涯
Oh you fall into a life sucking abyss.
或陷入悲剧的深渊
- Mmm Hmm.- So.
- 嗯 嗯 - 所以
It all depends on how you respond to my next two words.
一切都取决于你如何应对我的两个词
Impress me.
打动我
Now?
现在
Impress me.
打动我
You catch me off guard, I...
你让我措手不及 我...
Impress me.
打动我
I'm an open book, ask me any question you like.
我就像百科全书 问我你喜欢的任何问题
- So you're a go getter ramrod. - Yes sir.
- 那么你想要一展身手 - 是的 先生
Take charge kind of guy.
喜欢主动权的家伙
I'm a killer, a stone cold killer.
我是一个杀手 冷血杀手
So, take charge guy.
所以 主动权家伙
Take charge, Viking, barbarian.
主动 像维京人 野蛮人
Of course, it's me.
当然 那就是我
Pow! I'm here.
我在这里
We are not looking for that here.
我们这里可不需要这种人
No brown nosing, no suck up.
我们这里没有阿谀奉承
No toolery, I...
没有傀儡 我...
Yes, Mr. Brazos.
是的 布拉索斯先生
Um, why is Chantal using what appears to be,
嗯，为什么尚塔尔好像在红色的地板上
...a red cup from the red floor?
使用一个红色的杯子
- When we are on the yellow floor. - I'm on it.
- 我们的背景墙可是黄色的 -我就来了
It is a visual and therefore a visceral betrayal.
实在是太扎眼了 真是没纪律
Stop it.
扔了它
Such a dumb ass.
猪头
Disgusting.
恶心
Thank you.
谢谢
It's a total anarchy around here.
无法无天到我无法控制了
The uh, email I read said administrative aid.
呃，我看到电子邮件说招聘行政助理
Nope, mail room.
不 是收发室
I'm going to go.
我还是走吧
Uh, do you have any idea how many Ivy league,
你知道有多少人向往这个职位
- Phi Beta Kappa would kill... - Mister I saved your life twice.
- 甚至挤破脑袋...  - 先生 我拯救过两次危机
Okay, I can't tell you how or when.
好吧 我不能告诉你如何或何时
Or why, but I have done shit that matters.
或者为什么 但我做过这些狗屎事
And I'd just kinda like a job where I matter again.
我只想要找个工作而不是找麻烦
So thank you, but no thank you.
所以谢谢你 但也没什么好谢的
- Okay. -You know what I think?
- 好吧 - 你知道我怎么想？
You want the job after this job.
你想要放弃这次机会
But son, this is the job that's standing in your way.
但是孩子，这份职位就是给你准备的
And that's why you're going to be so very, very good at it.
由你来做将是非常、非常的合适
'Cause when I look at you.
因为我看着你
I see a younger me.
就想到年轻时候的我
Classified Nest Headquarters - Washington, D.C.
华盛顿特区  NEST秘密总部
All running Autobots in tar, training in 15 minutes.
所有行驶的汽车人 15分钟后开始训练
Dino report to bay 23.
Dino 到23号位置报道
Sideswipe bay 37 for weapons assessment.
横炮请到37号位置，准备武器评估
Senator, I suggest you remember that when the NASA
参议员 我建议如果航空航天局
...wants funding they call me.
需要资助让他们给我来个电话
When the CIA is going to take out a target.
中情局想干掉目标
They ask first for my permission.
必须也要有我的许可
When the President wants to know which members of Congress are politically vulnerable.
如果总统想知道对手的政治弱点
in terms of oh,  let's say undiscovered criminal conduct.
- 术语 - 也就是说，未被发现他有的犯罪行为
I'm on their memory dials.
也给我打电话
USA agency say they have been monitoring the blast.
美国政府表示 他们已经监测到爆炸
But in fact this was a covert military strike.
但实际上 这是个秘密的军事打击
- No nation has yet claimed ownership. - The CIA is up my ass about this mystery...
- 没有任何国家承认为其所做 - 中情局为这个秘密得来拍我马屁
..raid in the middle east. So it's time to come clean was the unit involved.
据说中央情报局正在交接处理中东事件
Uh, I'm not sure, Ma'am.
嗯 我不知道 夫人
All right guys, this is how you do a decepticon...
大家看清楚了么，这就是把霸天虎干掉的方法
...head kill shot.
...爆头的方法
As director of national intelligence
做为国家情报局主任
I'm a really big fan of intelligent answers.
我对报告很感兴趣
I...I can't really tell you definitively.
我...我不能告诉你确切的
These Autobots are like teenage kids.
这些汽车人就像十几岁的小孩
They like to sneak out of the house once in a while.
喜欢偷偷离家出走消失一段时间
Colonel Lennox, are you in command...
伦诺克斯上校 你是这里的指挥官...
- ...or are you not? - Yes, Ma'am. I am....
- 或者 不是你  - 是的 夫人 是我....
Stop with the Ma'am, enough with the Ma'am.
别叫我夫人 真受够了
Do I look like a Ma'am?
我看起来像个夫人吗
No, ma'am. Yes, ma'am, yes.
不 夫人 是的 长官 是的
- This one is a perfect invention I have made. - Right.
- 这个完美的发明我已经完成了  -太好了
Oh, good they're here.
哦 好 他们在这里
My names' Que. I do hope you have answers for him.
我名字叫Q 真希望你能给他一个交代
-I've never seen him so upset. - Optimus, you remember Charlotte Mearing?
- 我从来没有见过他如此郁闷 - 擎天柱 你还记得夏洛特梅琳吗
Our Director of National Intelligence.
国家情报局主任
He's in a bad mood.
他心情不好
He's a not want to talk-a to anybody today.
今天不想和任何人交谈
What is this?
这是什么意思
The silent treatment?
无言的反抗
We've seen that, and this is not that.
看上去是
This is worse.
事实上是更糟糕
Prime, make something of yourself.
大哥，尽情吐槽吧！
He's pissed.
他要发飚了
You lied to us.
你骗了我们
Everything humans' know of our planet we were told had all been shared.
我们把我们星球的一切都毫无保留的告诉你们
So why was this found in human possession?
可为什么你们却对我们有所隐瞒？
We were in the dark on this also.
我们也是被蒙在鼓里
It was director only clearance at Sector 7, until now.
直到现在为止 只第七区部门了解
- The bag. - Which bag?
-给我包  - 哪个包？
Air Ms. Berkin, green ostrich.
猪头，绿色鸵鸟皮那个
Oh my god.
噢 真服了你
This is a secret few men knew.
只有少数人知道这秘密
And fewer still remain alive.
他们几个都还活着
Allow me to please introduce to you,
请允许我为你介绍
two of NASA's founding mission directors.
美国宇航局研究项目主任
and astronaut, Dr. Buzz Aldrin.
宇航员奥尔德林博士
One of the first two men to step foot on the moon.
第一次登月行走的两人其中之一
Sir.
先生
Optimus Prime.
这位是擎天柱元老
From a fellow space traveler.
作为一名有过同样太空之旅的宇航员
It's a true honor.
见到你非常荣幸
The honor is mine.
同样荣幸
Our entire space race of the 1960's...
我们在六十年代的太空竞赛...
...it appears was in response to an event.
是这事件的导火线
Our astronauts investigated a crashed alien ship.
我们的宇航员探索坠毁的外星飞船时
No survivors on board.
并没有发现还有幸存者
We were sworn to secrecy by our commander in chief.
我们对总部发誓要保守秘密
This was a mission you will never speak of.
这是一个从来没有过的任务
I understand, sir.
我明白 先生
A total of 35 people knew the real plan at NASA.
共有35人知道航空航天局真正的目的
Soviets managed to land unmanned probes.
苏联发送无人太空船到月球
Somehow they must have picked up that fuel rod.
不知为什么 他们好像捡到了燃料棒
We believe the Russians deduced that the rod was a fissionable fuel assembly.
我们相信俄国推断这是可分裂的燃料物
Believed they had it mastered and harnessed it at Chernobyl.
这很可能就是被用来当切尔诺贝利核电站的核能原料
We went on six missions in all.
我们被派出六次侦测任务
We took hundreds of photos and samples.
采集了数以百计的照片和样品
We locked them away forever.
这些我们永久封存了
And the moon program was shut down.
而登月的后续的计划被取消
Where did you search the crash hold?
是我们在现场发现的那东西
The ships name was the ARK.
飞船的名字叫方舟
I watched it escape Cybertron myself.
我亲眼看着它逃离赛博坦
It was carrying an Autobot technology which would have won us the war.
据说他搭载了汽车人可以赢得这场战争的科技
And its captain.
还有船长
- Who was this captain? - The Great Sentinel Prime.
- 谁是船长 - 伟大的御天敌元老
The technology's inventor.
他是这项技术的发明者
He was commander of the Autobots.
曾是汽车人领袖
Before me.
我的前任
It's imperative that I find it before the Decepticons learn of its location.
当务之急必须尽快赶在霸天虎之前找到他
Our Autobot space craft has the ability to get there.
我们汽车人的飞船可以赶到那里
And, you must pray it's in time.
还有，你必须祈祷这一切还来得及
Hi, I'm here to see Carly Spenser.
嗨 我来找Carly斯宾塞
You got the job?
你找到工作了
- This is crazy. - You really got it?
- 真是太疯狂了 - 你真的找到了
- Yes. - See what did I tell you, it's the bunny.
- 是的 - 看 我告诉过你 是幸运的兔子
You are so welcome.
你真是个香饽饽
- Do you like me a little more? - A little bit, yeah.
- 你会喜欢我多一点吗  - 是的 一点点
I want to see the curator.
我想见见你领导
- I want to see the guy in space mountain. - I know, isn't it beautiful in here.
- 想见识下拥有这所太空城的家伙  - 我知道 给你介绍我老板
And he's the coolest guy, ever.
还有他是个很酷的家伙
- Yeah.  - Yeah.
- 是吗   - 是啊
Sam.
Dylan Gould.
Hey.
嘿
Pleasure to meet you.
很高兴认识你
Pleasure meeting you.
幸会
Carly has told me a lot about you.
Carly告诉了我很多关于你的事
Well, visa versa. It's a beautiful building you got.
呵呵，你这里的建筑可真是美丽时尚啊
The Star Ship Enterprise here.
太空船企业总部就在这里
Thank you very much, it leaks.
非常感谢，不要泄露出去
Ah, before Carly came to help on the collection it was just a complete mess.
在Carly来帮助收藏之前 这里是一团糟
But now the restorations are back on track.
但现在又回到正轨了
I'm going to pebble beach this year, going to need a trophy for that stand right there.
我今年要去圆石滩 并且将会带回来一个奖杯放在那里
You know why?
你知道为什么吗
Because this woman right here,
因为站在那的女人
...is my secret weapon.
是我的秘密武器
- Okay. - Mr. Gould please, you exaggerate.
- 好吧 - 古尔德先生 拜托 你夸大其词了
All I've done is get you organized.
我所做的仅仅是把它收集起来而已
Oh you have done much more than that, my Duchess.
哦 你做得不仅是如此 我的公爵夫人
Nicknames, that's fun.
昵称 这很有趣
Yeah, the Duchess
是啊 公爵夫人
She's adorable.
她可真可爱
You know when I stole her away from the British Embassy,
你知道当我从英国大使馆挖角过来
I said, it's easy to manage a country.
我对他们说 处理一个国家事务很容易
Try managing a priceless collection of art.
但来试试管理无价的收藏艺术品
Take a look at this 1939 Delahaye 165 Cabriolet
来看看这个 1939 Delahaye 165敞篷车
Designed by a French man.
是法国人设计的
Look at the curves, elegant isn't it.
看这曲线 真优雅 是吧
Beautiful
美丽
Sensual.
性感
Built to evoke the body of the ideal woman.
据说构想来自性感女人的曲线
Come on.
来吧
My dad had a ten dollar desk and a dream.
我爸爸有张十元的书桌和一个梦想
And he built it into an empire.
他把它建成一个帝国
- Wow. - We're the largest accounting firm in the US.
- 哇 - 我们是美国最大的会计师事务所
Mine started off the adventure side after he passed.
在他辛苦打拼后，由我来接手开始提供资金
Thatin the future.
投资于未来
Try and bet on the winners.
努力成为赢家
See collecting cars helps me keep my sanity.
收集名车一直是我的爱好
These look great.
这些看起来棒极了
Oh, that was a great day, Mr. Gould.
哦 真是伟大的一天 古尔德先生
- I didn't see that one. - No, me either.
- 我没有看过这个 - 是 我也是
Games are tight.
花样可真多
Oh, here we go, here we go.
哦 好了 走吧
You see that?
你看到了吗
Judgment, judge to my car.
鄙视一下 鄙视一下我的车
You going to wait on him while he's judging me?
你们可以一边狗腻一边鄙视我
What's with you? He's my boss.
你怎么了 他是我的老板
He still pays for our food, our rent.
我们吃的用的都是他给的
No, I totally understand.
喔 我彻底明白了
I'm totally fine, I get it. I'm well fed.
我很好 没事 我能养活自己
Guess what, I'm not your boy toy anymore. I got my big boy pants on now.
想啥呢 我不再是你的玩具了 我还换了西裤
You see them?
看到了吗
In the car, thank you Duchess.
上车吧  谢谢公爵夫人
Oh, my god, are you threatened by him?
哦 天啊 你吃醋了
啊哈哈.....
Threatened, what am I threatened by? His money, his power, his good looks?
吃醋 我吃什么醋 因为他有钱 有权 人长的帅
None of the above, check!
狗屁！打住
Your temper tantrums are so sexy.
你生气的样子太性感了
Get in the car, please.
请上车
Sam, he's hardly the first man to ever smile at me.
Sam 他又不是第一个对我笑的人
I think I can handle it.
我想我可以处理好我们的关系
Hold on, hold on. It's..it's the smiling back part that gets me.
等等 我就受不了他那淫笑
- Okay. - No more smiles.
- 好吗 - 不再微笑
Never again, I promise.
不会再有了 我保证
You see, that works for me.
你看，又他妈打不着火了
Easy, easy.
慢点 慢点
You're not going to get it started that way.
这样做是发不动的
What, I was just getting it ready. I'm about 32% done with my restoration.
我这是在准备修复 现在大约恢复了32％
Chrome work, put a spoiler on the back, done deal.
给我个烙铁我就能搞定他
You know Carly's been telling me you've been struggling job loss.
Carly告诉我 你好像一直在求职
Just so you know.
还是告诉你吧
I'm on the board for Accuretta systems.
我在Accuretta系统的董事会
And I put in a call for you.
是我让他们打电话给你
Just keep it between us, okay.
这事只有我们知道 好不好
She's so kind to me.
她对我很温柔
You're a lucky man.
幸运的小子
Xanthium approaching Tranquility base.
苍耳号接近宁静海基地
Here's Houston, you're a go Xanthium.
这里是休斯顿 你们去吧 苍耳号
Armstrong, having a good day.
阿姆斯特朗 拥有美好的一天
Ratchet, let's roll.
救护车 我们出发
Did they get that mag cap on?
他们戴上安全帽了吗
Copy contact.
保持联系
We're entering the Ark.
我们进入了方舟
His levels are faint.
他的生命信号很微弱
Locked himself away.
他把自己封闭
To guard the pillars.
以保护这些能源棒
Sentinel.
御天敌
You're coming home, old friend.
我们回家吧 老朋友
All hail, Megatron.
万岁 威震天
My master, it's master.
主人回来了  是主人
Ah, don't be greedy.
哦 不要贪心
My fragile ones.
我脆弱的朋友
You look poor, Master.
你看上去很糟糕啊，老大
How it pains me to see you so vulnerable
是什么让我眼中的你变得如此痛苦
- So weak. - Spare me you gaseous sycophant.
- 如此脆弱 - 滚开，马屁精
You know what you were told. Resist nothing.
就知道卖弄嘴皮，没用的东西
Soundwave reporting, Lord Megatron.
声波报到 威震天大人
And what news from my assassin?
我的小密探，有什么新闻
Autobots have taken the bait.
汽车人中计了
They discovered the Ark, and returned with its cargo.
他们找到了方舟飞船，并把货物带去了芝加哥总部
You did me great honor, tracking that ship to the moon.
干的漂亮 继续监视方舟
Your human collaborators have served their purpose, Soundwave.
那些和人类的合作者忌日到了 声波
It's time to eliminate loose ends.
是时候该了结这一切了
Laserbeak, kill them all.
找到他们 斩草除根
With pleasure.
乐意之至
Is your daddy home?
你爸爸在家吗
Then the daddy said it's our time.
爸爸马上回来...
Hello, mom.
你好 妈妈
Get out of the house!
滚出我家
- What are you doing in my house? - Just visiting.
- 你在我的房子里做什么 - 只是拜访
What's this hoochee around here?
为什么工牌会在这里？
- Just because (Speaking Spanish) - No
- 这是因为... - 不行
- This is the aerospace baby.
- 这是航空事业局，宝贝
You are not allowed back here.
你不要再来了
New guy, you see that?
新人，你看到了吗
That's a Latin melt down, okay.
这是一个拉丁女
You ever show up in my office with a regional outfit you're fired.
如果在办公室放东西就会被解雇
You got that, okay?
明白了吗
If you're going to be on this job for 2 1/2 years, okay I want you to live it, love it and made it.
你要在这里呆二年半，我要你记住，学会适应
There's no ladder climbing in my office. I run a tight ship.
在我的办公室不要攀龙附凤 明白吗
- Yes, sir. - Okay, so move.
- 是的 先生 - 好了 快工作
I found that paper I was telling you about.
我告诉你的事今天见报了
What are you looking at?
你在看什么
SHUT UP!
闭嘴
You do that to me again and I'll kick your ass.
你再这样对我 我会踢你菊花
- Hi Angel. - Hello.
- 嗨 天使 - 你好
I had a meeting downtown, is it okay for me to stop by?
在市区有个会议 我顺道过来看看
I don't know my 500 page employee conduct manual isn't exactly a page turner.
我手忙脚乱的 那500页员工手册还没看完
This is grey.
真悲惨
Autobots are out there saving the world, and I organize four binders.
汽车人在外面拯救世界 我却被绑在这里
It may be a dream, come on.
这只是个梦想 来吧
Visitor violation.
违规的访客
You okay?
你还好吗
Absolutely.
当然
I'm next.
换我了
Listen, Saturday.
听着 星期六
There's a party at the house it's a work thing, but Dylan's invited you too.
有个派对 虽然是公事 但Dylan邀请了你
Really, oh did he.
真的 是吗
No need to come off with bad jokes. It would really mean a lot to me, okay.
就算你过去说上几句玩笑话，我也不介意
I'd love to go. How did you get over here?
我会喜欢去的 你怎么来的
A car.
开车
You don't have a car.
你没有车子
Yes I do.
有 我有
What, did you win it in a raffle?
怎么 你中奖了
Uh, he gave me one.
嗯 他给了我一辆
He gave you a car?
他给你一辆车
Yeah, I think it was a work perk.
是的 我认为这是为了提升士气
Hmm, a work perk.
嗯 工作士气
What kind of car did he gave you?
他给你辆什么车
- Um, a Mercedes SLS AMG. - Mmm, hmm.
- 嗯 一辆宾士 SLS AMG -嗯 嗯
Really crazy engine.
引擎很棒
Mercedes Benz SLS.
宾士 SLS
You rode this here?
你开到这里了
It's a $200,000 Car.
这可是20万美元的车子
I know.
我知道
You know how long it would take me to afford a car like this?
你知道要多久 我才能买得起这种车吗
- Long time. - Yeah like, 53 years.
- 很长的时间 - 是的 大概53年
You said it was a perk, first.
他说提高士气第一优先
You know what we should do? We should sell it and buy a house.
我觉得我们应该卖掉它来买房子
You're frustrated, I know.
你又不高兴了 我知道
I've been there.
我都习惯了
It's called paying your dues.
这就是所谓的交会费
Good things will happen.
一切都会变好的
Ladies and gentlemen.
女士们 先生们
I need some lunchtime filing done, stat.
我需要做些午餐时间的加班
Who would like to score some Bruce Brazos points?
谁想与布鲁斯布拉索斯一起加班
Bruce, you found your guy.
布鲁斯 你找到你伙计了
Witwicky.
维特维奇
The man who makes this company run.
一位让这家公司运转的男人
Now who have we here, a sister, facebook friend?
现在谁到我们这里了 一个妹子 网友？
Twitter, tweeter.
不停地唠唠叨叨
- Carly this is Bruce. Bruce. - Hi.
- Carly这位是布鲁斯 - 布鲁斯 - 嗨
I'm his girlfriend, pleasure to meet you.
我是他的女朋友 很高兴见到你
Sam was right, you really do have smashing head of hair.
Sam说得对 你头发很有型
- Well thank you. - Your welcome.
- 嗯 谢谢你 - 别客气
Sam I gotta run.
Sam 我得走了
Here, your present.
这里 你的礼物
Your favorite color.
你最喜欢的颜色
Nice to meet you Mr. Brazos.
很高兴认识你 布拉索斯先生
And you.
我也是
See ya boys.
再见 男孩
I'm still stewing about that binder incident, Jerry.
我仍然忧虑关于粘结剂的事情 Jerry
May I finish my Chu Wah milk, Tony.
我可以喝完我的舒化奶吗 托尼
I dont care about your exotic milk.
我可不在乎你的异国情调奶
I care about respect.
我在乎的是尊重
I know who you are.
我知道你是谁
Wicky, Witwicky.
维基 维特维奇
- You know who, I'm talking to you. - Excuse me.
- 我知道你 我跟你说话呢 - 对不起
Thank you.
谢谢
No, no, slow down tiger.
不 不 慢点 猛虎
You showed up on the back of six different photos.
六张特殊照片不同的地点都有你的身影
Two continents worth of aliens.
横跨两大洲还有外星人
And I ordered you in Egypt.
我确定你去过埃及
Huh, right.
咦 对吗
Because you know the Aliens.
因为你认识那些外星人
See ya.
再见
One check.
等会
Hey, I am Wang, Deep Wang.
嘿 我是王 王深
Deep Wang.
王深
You're not getting it, "Deep Throat".
不是你想的那个 "深喉"
Okay, cause they told you.
好了，因为他们告诉你
Shhh, they watch and listen.
嘘 他们在监视
I can't go to the government.
我不能去政府
You, you can because shit's going down.
但是你，你能 因为糟糕的事来了
Son, it is code pink and in 'Floyd'.
孩子 它是在"弗洛伊德"中的粉红色代码
Dark side, why do you think no ones been up there since 1972.
黑暗的一面 你想为什么自1972以来就再没有人到那里
You speak in English, it's a very strange English.
你说的英语 是非常奇怪的英语
That's why un. oh....oh.
这就是为什么 哦....哦
Don't, I'm gonna hit ya.
不要 我会揍它
Well I'm going to hit ya right back, son.
好吧 等哈再来揍它 孩子
That's my manifesto.
这是我的宣言
Your riding this out.
你把这散播出去
Everyone in the original is in the dark.
在黑暗中到处都是原形
Alien friends is in danger. You know the good ones, it's up to you.
你的外星人朋友处于危险中 你懂得 就看你了
Easy, Sam.
轻点 Sam
What are you looking at?
你在看什么呢
Yow, dog.
哼 狗
Did you look at my shit?
你在看着我吗
Who are you working for?
你为谁工作
Stare down, you and me.
看我的眼睛
Guess I won.
猜 我赢了
Moons ... list.
月亮... 名单
More suspends program.
很多延缓的计划
Experts dead.
专家死了
Space Program ends.
太空计划结束
Dark side.
黑暗的一面
Dark side of the moon.
月亮的黑暗面
Look what I found outside the bathroom, huh?
看看我在浴室外面发现的
It yours? Deal with this.
是你的吗  处理掉
Yes, sir.
是的 先生
I did everything you want.
我没有你想要的一切
I really think we should talk, because some of the stuff...
我觉得我们应该谈谈  因为有些东西...
Whoa, knock first.
哇 首先请敲门
Can't you see I'm busy.
你没看见我正在忙
Who are you, who are you?
你是谁 你是谁
You straddled me in the stall.
你在厕所上了我
That happened to me once in this life, I wouldn't forget it.
这是我此生的第一次 我永远不会忘记
- No, no. - In the bathroom stall.
- 没有 没有 - 在厕所马桶上
You pulled your package out.
你拉开你的拉锁
Whoa, whoa, we are not boyfriends, okay.
哇 哇 我们不是基佬 好吗
One phone call from me and I'll have you fired.
我要打电话投诉，我要解雇你
Oh yes I will, Gaylord.
哦 是 我会的 盖洛德
You okay?
你还好吗
It's a hemorrhoid.
是个痔疮
Should I come back? When should I come back?
我需要回来了吗 我该什么时候回来
Come back when you learn some manners.
当你学会礼貌时再回来
I don't know him, I would never say anything.
我不认识他 我什么也没说
Whoa, whoa, whoa, okay, okay.
哇 等等 哇 好 好
Something would tell us, just like I promised.
有人会告诉我们 就像我答应的
I will blind on the perimeter.
我会让周围视而不见
What more do you want from me?
你还想从我这里得到什么
Gerry.
Jerry
You are my favorite.
你是我的最爱
I'll do whatever you want me to do.
我会做任何你想要我做的事
I know.
我知道
My superiors need me to....
我的上司需要我....
- What? - Suicide you.
- 什么 -让你自杀
What did you say to Witwicky?
你和维特维奇说了什么
Shit.
妈的
Huh, who want's some chicken dinner now, bitch?
哼 谁想来些烤鸡晚餐 混蛋
'Cause somebody messed with the wrong Wang today.
因为今天有人把王先生看扁了
Come on, you want some of me.
拜托 你还需要我
I don't need anymore didactic lectures from Chuck.
我不要再去听查克的教学讲座
Jesus!
卧槽
Get legal.
快去报案
That's Jerry.
是Jerry
Come on people, yes, a workmate died.
拜托 是的 一位同事挂了
But looking out windows is not going to bring him back.
但站在那看是不会让他活过来的
The man was depressed.
这哥们想不开
Don't take a picture.
别拍了
You can keep watching him but he's not getting up.
你可以继续看着他 但他起不来了
You all read Humpty Dumpty.
你们都理解矮胖子
Okay.
好了
Witwicky.
维特维奇
When this comes out in the press, you clean up. Wang is everywhere.
当媒体来时，你要收拾干净已经粉身碎骨的王
He is in the beast the bang goo.
他曾像头困兽
He over the Apollo strait.
现在他自由了
Did you see the sidewalk down there?
你看到人行道下了吗
Man.
伙计
You forget his person, his name his parking space.
你忘了这家伙吧 他的名字是个空白
Hey, when did we get a new copier?
嘿 我们什么时候又进了台新复印机
Did he say anything about what I saw?
难道要我说出我看到的吗
Who you share a toilet stall with is totally your business.
有人和你在厕所共用一个马桶
This is exceedingly Japanese.
这是日本货吧
They never make it easy.
一向都不好操作
What is with you?
你怎么了
This is the really deal, Carly.
出大事了 Carly
Okay, I need you to stay composed.
好的，我需要你保持镇静
It's real life, I'll explain to you later.
这是真实的 稍后我会解释
We got an emergency, you gotta get Colonel X in here.
有紧急状况 我要见伦诺克斯上校
On point decepticons, the deceptions are back again.
霸天虎 霸天虎又回来了
- You gotta open that gate up right now. - Easy, sir.
- 你快打开大门，赶紧的 - 别紧张 先生
This is health and human services.
这里是卫生和社会服务单位
Right, packing M-4's?
好啊 装备M4冲锋枪？
What are you protecting, Colostomy bags?
你们想保护什么？十二指肠？
- Bed pans, throat lozenges? - Mybe.
- 坐骨神经还是扁桃腺？ - 或许吧
Where did you get that hat from? Nursing school?
还有这帽子哪弄来的？ 从护士学院？
So your nurses and foot powder protection.
所以作为你们保护奖励送给你们的
- Oh fantastic, yes.- Baby, I dont think we're in....
- 哦 太棒了是的 - 亲爱的，我认为我们不是...
- ..the right place. - We are in the right place.
- ...找错了  - 就是这里
We are in the right place.
我们就要到这里
We are in the right place, and I want to talk to Optimus right now.
现在就请让我们进去，我要找擎天柱说话！
- You're going to get me Optimus right now. - I'm sure you got the wrong building.
- 现在马上让我见擎天柱 - 我想你弄错地方了
I don't know what you're talking about.
我不知道你在说什么
What part of the Deceptions are back don't you understand?
那些该死的霸天虎又回来了 你听懂了吗
Yo!
你！
You're being a smart ass.
你这个聪明混球
Do not hit my car, it's a collector's item.
不要打我的车 这是我的收藏古董
I wouldn't do that.
我可不会这么做
You're crazy.
你疯了
We got an Energon reading.
探测到数据
I got readings in the vehicle.
在车上探测到辐射
- Freeze! -Whoa, whoa, whoa, we're freezing.
- 不许动 - 哇 哇 哇 我们没有动
Are you...
你...
Please get out of the car.
拜托 离开车子
- I got him, go. - 'B'!
- 我抓住他了，带走 -大黄！
Is 'B' in there?
大黄蜂 你在哪？
- Okay, you got me. - Stay down.
- 好吧 你抓住我了 - 停下来
This how you treat Autobots?
这就是你们对待汽车人的方式？
We're on the same team.
我们可是一伙的
Yeah, enjoy your next job at 7-11, dickhead.
是啊，准备享受无尽的加班吧 笨蛋
- That's right.- A-hole.
- 没错 - 白痴
How's your car now?
你的车现在怎么了
That's my car.
这才是我的车
Come here.
过来
Come here!
Come on...Sam.
（拜托...Sam）
What is your deal, huh?
这就是你要做的吗
I know your black ops stuff is important.
我知道你当秘密特工很重要
You know I'm not trying to diminish it, or guilt trip you, or anything.
你知道我不是要消遣你或什么的
But I just never see you anymore.
但我再也没有见到你了
You can't come to the garage and stay on one night?
你能来车库并呆一个晚上吗
Sam, that makes me feel bad.
（Sam 这让我很不好受）
Yeah, well I hope you feel bad, you should feel bad.
是啊 我就希望你不好受 你就应该心疼
Look at the jalopy I'm driving now.
看看我现在开的老爷车
I feel bad every single day.
我每天都感到很难受
Yo let's go, both of you.
你 你们俩个都走吧
Lennox want's to see you.
伦诺克斯要见你
What, we're not good enough for you anymore.
（什么 我们也不比你好过）
Sorry babe, they were very rude, right.
抱歉 宝贝 他们都是帮粗人对吧
And you're fixing my car.
你负责修好我的车
You don't think so?
你有意见？
Raise your hand if you had a flying psycho ninja copier try to kill you today.
- 抬手 - 今天差点被一个忍者影印机杀了
Those are my brass knuckles.
这些是我的脚镯子
That's my anklet do I have to take that off too?
这是我的脚镯子 也要拿掉吗？
And my toe rings?
那我的脚戒指呢？
All exhibitions clear the floor. We have ten minutes until attempted contact.
清除地板所有杂物 还有十分钟准备接触
We've taken possession of the five devices that were hidden in the ship.
我们找到5个御天敌元老隐藏在飞船上的设施
of Sentinel Prime.
御天敌拼命藏起来的东西
They're some kind of prototype Autobot technology.
这些都是一些汽车人的原始技术
They say Sentinel was the Einstein of his civilization.
他们说，御天敌就好比是爱因斯坦
So we're going to keep these locked up,
所以我们要把这些锁起来
...until we know what we're dealing with.
直到我们知道怎么处理
Right now no one gets access.
现在没有人能够接近
- No one. - This morning a guy recognized me.
- 没有任何人 - 今天早上有个家伙认出了我
He told me to warn you, he's talking about the Dark side of the moon.
他要我警告你 还谈到了月球的阴暗面
- Then they killed him. - Wait a minute, you mentioned the moon?
- 然后他被杀害了 - 等等 你们谈到关于月球？
Yeah, dark side of the moon.
是的 月亮的阴暗面
But why would the decepticons want to kill humans?
但是 霸天虎为什么要杀害人类
I thought their war was with the Autobots.
我以为他们只和汽车人过不去
And that is when he made his quick book town report. That's what I want..
然后 他写了这个初步的科学报告...
Who's the chick, okay.
那只小鸡是谁？
Excuse me, Colonel Lennox.
对不起 伦诺克斯上校
Director Mearing
梅琳主任
This is Sam Witwicky.
这是Sam维特维奇
- A civilian c.. - I know his name, Colonel.
- 普通百姓... - 我知道他是谁 上校
I want to know who gave him clearance.
我想知道是谁让他进来的
Who gave me Clearance? How about Optimus Prime.
谁放我进来 是擎天柱行了吧
When he touched down in suburbia looking for my house.
那时候他降落在郊区找到我家
This is the national intelligence director.
这是国家情报局主管
In case you..
警告你..
- Hi. - Disrespecting a federal officer.
- 嗨 - 不要对联邦官员失礼
That ought to get you somewhere, who's she?
这是你应该来的地方吗 她是谁
She's my girlfriend.
她是我的女朋友
What is this like a date?
今天是什么日子
She knows all about the Autobots, okay.
她知道所有汽车人的事情 好吗
She knows Bumblebee, and comes from a military family.
她知道大黄蜂 而且出自一个军人家庭
I can vouch for her.
我能担保她
Hey, I have an idea.
嘿 我有个主意
How bout we get back to the important topics?
我们回到重要的议题如何
Like the fact I almost had my face cut off by a Decepticon.
譬如今天我的连就差点被霸天虎撕了
As a tax payer I can lodge a complaint.
作为纳税人 我这是在投诉
- As a matter of fact. - Okay, listen.
- 这是事实  - 好吧 听着
One of the software engineers at Sams office was murdered today.
今天在Sam的办公室一个工程师被谋杀
He was involved in NASA's Lunar mapping probe.
他参与了太空总署的月球探测计划
Here's the thing, Colonel Lennox.
东西在这里 伦诺克斯上校
We cannot entrust national security to teenagers.
我们不能把国家的安全交给乳臭未干的小孩
Unless I missed the policy paper.
除非我错过了政策文件
Are we doing that now?
现在我们还这样做吗
No, good.
不 很好
I don't care who you are.
我不在乎你是谁
If you breathe a word of what you've seen here.
如果你把这里看到的到处乱说
You will do time for treason.
我就以叛国罪搞死你
Do you understand me?
明白么
I'll take my orders from the Autobots. I know them, I don't know you.
我比你更熟悉汽车人 我了解他们 可我不认识你
You will.
你会的
Sentinel Prime.
御天敌元老
He seems to run on Energon, and he's out of it.
它似乎没有足够的能量
He's in a sort of a sleep mode.
看上去就像待机了
Let us begin.
让我们开始吧
It's the great matrix of leadership.
这就是传说中的领导模块
He holds the only thing in the universe that can repower a Transformers spark.
宇宙中超牛B的能量，可以激活火种
This is incredible.
真不可思议
Sentinel Prime.
御天敌元老
We bid you return.
我们恭迎您归来
Revenge.
复仇
- No. - Just fire at.
- 不  -别开枪
No, Sentinel.
不 御天敌
It is I, Optimus Prime.
是我，柱子
It is all right.
全都没事了
You are safe.
你是安全的
There's nothing to fear.
没有什么可担心的了
We are here.
我们都在这里
You are home, Sentinel.
你到家了，御天敌
The war?
战争？
The war!
战争怎样了
The war was lost.
战争失败了
Cybertron is now but a barren wasteland.
赛博坦现在一片荒芜
We have taken refuge here on Planet Earth.
我们到地球这里避难
Its human race is our allies.
他们是人类 我们的盟友
My ship?
我的船呢
We came under fire.
我们遭到攻击
The pillars.
能源棒
Where are the pillars?
能源棒在哪里
You saved five of them.
你只救了五支
Including the control pillar.
里面包括控制能源棒
Only five?
只有五支？
We once had hundreds.
我们带来数百支
Excuse me, gentlemen. May I ask, what is this technology you're looking for?
打断一下，先生们，问个问题 你们在探讨什么科技
It is the ability to reshape the universe.
这是一种可以改变宇宙空间的技术
Together the pillars form a space bridge.
这些能源棒可以用来架设太空桥
I designed and I alone can control it.
这是我的设计由我自行控制它
It defied your laws of physics to transport matter through time and space.
它可以无视常理通过时间和空间进行大规模传输
You're talking about a teleportation device, aren't you?
你说的是隐形传输设备 是吗
Yes, for resources, for refuges.
是的  用于资源 避难
Refuges or troops of soldiers.
避难或部队的士兵
Weapons, maybe bombs.
武器 也许炸弹
A means of an instant strike, that's its military function, isn't it?
一种瞬间的打击方法 这是其军事功能 不是吗
It is our technology.
这是我们的技术
And it must be returned.
它必须归还给我们
Yes, if humans say so.
是的 除非人类同意
You can't just bring weapons of mass destruction into our atmosphere.
你不能把大规模毁灭性武器带入大气层
Kind of have to declare customs first.
除非获得许可
A little formality called paperwork.
符合要求的合法形式声明
Kinda separates us from the animals.
不要以为我们是低等动物
I will overlook your condescending tone.
你的口气让我相当蛋疼
You heave the gravity of mine.
算了，老夫原谅你的无礼
The decepticons must never know the space bridge is here.
但是绝不能让霸天虎知道这里有一个太空桥
For in their hands...
如果到了他们的手中...
...it would mean the end of your world.
...那就意味着你们的世界末日到了
Total my mear file.
给我那个文件夹
So the investigation is open.
因此 我们已经开始调查了
We sent agents to your office.
并给你公司布置了探员
And for the time being, we're going to send you home with Autobot protection.
还会派汽车人保护你回家
Wh..who do I need to speak to, to get you guys to understand I can help.
我可以跟谁说 能让你们明白我可以帮忙
I can contribute.
我可以尽份力
Hey we can all help you tell me what you know, I can tell you all the fun planets I've been.
嘿 我们都可以帮你，告诉你想知道的 我还可以告诉你曾经去过的行星和趣事
Get off my desk, please.
请从我的办公桌下来
Aw, you pulling out guns. Okay, can't help you on that.
喔 你拔枪了 行，这样不能帮你了
What do you envision with me? I go back home now, I make copies?
你就不能考虑下我么？我现在回家，继续过重复的日子？
This is a unit for veteran intelligence officers and special forces.
这是个资深情报员和特种部队的部门
Not for boys who once owned special cars.
不是专为曾经有辆特种车的男孩设的
That's a bit harsh, isn't it ma'am?
这有点苛刻 不是吗 夫人
Don't call me ma'am, I'm not a ma'am.
不要叫我夫人 我不是夫人
But you're a woman, aren't you?
但你是一个女人 不是吗
Sooo.
那么...
Are those yours?
那全是你的
Yeah, CIA.
是的 美国中央情报局
I only ask because I also have a medal.
我只是问问 因为我也有一枚奖牌
From the President.
总统颁的
Yeah.
是啊
Great, so it's not that complicated, right?
太好了 所以这不是那么复杂 对吗
No one gets to work with the Autobots unless I approve it.
没有人会跟汽车人一起工作 除非我批准
You're breaking my chain of command.
你打破了行规
Come on, let's go.
来吧 我们走吧
You've done what you can for them.
你做了你该做的
With all due respect, young man.
我尊重你年轻人
I appreciate what you did.
我很欣赏你的所作所为
But you're not a soldier.
但你不是战士
You're a messenger, you've always been a messenger.
你只是一个毛头，一个传话的
He's a hero.
他是个英雄
B, you take the freight elevator, I'll see you up there.
大黄 你坐货运电梯 在上面见
Ah, this blows.
啊 这是个打击
- That lady officially kicked us out. - Yeah.
- 那位小姐完全踢开我们 - 是啊
Witness protection program sucks.
证人保护方案通过，你妹！
Yeah, but we're a whole lot safer with big yellow and his cannons.
是的 但我们和大黄蜂及他的大炮一起会更有安全感
That dog can't protect crap.
你这是狗屁保护啊
B.
大黄
You couldn't sleep.
你睡不着
Yeah, me too.
是啊 我也一样
I don't believe she called me a messenger.
真不敢相信她说我只是个传话的
Do you believe that? After everything I've done, I'm a messenger.
你相信吗  我已经做了那么多 不过就是个传话的
Oh I believe it. I tell ya Sammy we feel the same way.
哦 我信你 Sam 我们感同身受
The disrespect on this rock is criminal.
那个傻逼不懂得什么是尊重
We should do something about it.
我们应该采取些行动
B.
大黄
I need to know why they're killing humans.
我需要知道他们为什么要杀死人类
What say we call in the expert?
那些所谓的专家
My next guest, is a former American intelligence operative.
我的下位嘉宾 是前美国情报人员
Who has dared to speak out.
一个敢于直言的人
Regarding our alleged military alliance,
关于我们所称的军事同盟
..which what many describe, as a group of extraterrestrial mercenaries.
还有那些外星雇佣军团请您透漏些更多的内情
He is the author of the best selling book,
他是本畅销书的作者
..."Code-Name Hero".
书名叫“密码英雄”
For our special agent, Seymour Simmons.
我们的特务 西摩西蒙斯
Bill, big fan. Great to be here.
比尔 非常荣幸来到这里
That is what you would have us to believe.
这就是你想试图说服我们的
It is in our best interest to formally take sides.
我们必须选择正确的立场
in this so called, alien civil war?
在这个所谓的外星人争端里？
Well, the other side wanted to spank us for breakfast, so.
好的，我没人愿意在早餐时被就废话弄得倒胃口，所以
I wouldn't exactly want to call it a toss up.
我会尽量简单解释这个问题
These decepticons are lethal.
霸天虎都是危险分子
But polls show half the world would feel safer with the Autobots completely gone.
但民调显示 世界有一半的人觉得汽车人完全消失了更安全
Get them out of here.
让他们滚！
We don't need them here.
我们不需要他们在这里
I feel safer when I sleep with a hand grenade.
当我和一枚手榴弹睡一样会有安全感
It doesn't mean I'm always right.
但并不表示我永远是对的
Thank you. Here's a fact, we obtained documents.
谢谢 这就是真相 我们获得资料
That shows you were fired by the intelligence committee.
上面说了你被情报单位解雇了
Down sized Bill, budget cuts.
裁员 比尔 为了削减预算
- Get, out. - It says before, Severe delusional,
- 滚开 -上面还说你有严重妄想
- ...tendencies. - This is ambush journalism.
- ...的倾向 - 这是诽谤
You want the truth about the alien alliance?
你想了解外星人联盟的真相吗
Buy my book.
买我的书吧
Buy my book!
快买我的书！
Before it's to late, people.
现在还不晚
You want a piece of me Bill, you want me to get naked?
你想让我出糗吗 比尔
- I'm ready, interview is over. - You sound like a pin-head agent.
- 我准备好了 访问结束  - 这听起来就像推销广告
-  and I got a suggestion for you. - get out of my house, it is over, understand?
- 我给你一个建议 - 滚出我家 已经结束了 知道吗
Damage control.
请克制一下自己
- Dutch! -  You have obviously upset Mr. Simmons.
- Dutch - 你明显心很烦 西蒙斯先生
You have 23 seconds to leave the property.
你有23秒离开我家
I have called the police.
我已经报了警
You are peasant people throwing rocks at a giant.
你这是搬石头砸自己的脚
What's up next, what have we got?
下一步呢 我们要做什么
Book signing midtown at noon, then your pic reality show for discovery HM.
中午市中心签名会 然后在探索频道真人秀
Oh and I had this, um...um.
哦 还有这个 嗯...嗯
The Vicky who keeps calling me five times today.
还有维特维奇今天打电话找了你5次
The kid, what does he want?
这小鬼 他想干嘛？
I called because the decepticons are back and I want to know why, and I need your help.
我打给你是因为霸天虎们回来了 我想知道真相 我需要你的帮助
They're back?
他们回来了
Well, that's good for business.
这关我毛的事啊
What if I told you I know a 50 year old alien secret that nobody ever told you?
如果我告诉你一个你从来不知道的50年前关于外星人的秘密呢？
Do not tempt my addiction.
不要吊我的胃口
I have gone through withdrawal, kid.
我不做探子很多年 孩子
Dutch, is this line secure?
Dutch 这条连线安全吗
No.
不
Don't take the risk.
不要冒这个险
I'm rich, why should I?
咱不差钱 我这是为什么？
Do not relapse, I won't.
不要再陷进去 我不会的
Do not let the demons win.
不要被魔鬼诱惑
Got.
接上了
What kind of....secret?
...是什么样的秘密
Apollo, moon, aliens, cover-up...
阿波罗 月亮 外星人 掩饰...
...future tech, assassinations, that kind of stuff.
...未来的高科技 暗杀 那类的
Oh, Apollo.
哦 阿波罗
Dutch!
Dutch
Tell Megatron, let's tango.
告诉威震天 让我们跳场探戈吧
So majestic and peaceful, this planet.
这个星球是如此的壮丽与和平
Unlike the final days of Cybertron.
不像我们已死去的故乡赛博坦
I've wondered what might have been.
我不知道会是什么样子
If you had fought the final battle.
也许是另外一个不同的结果
Instead of me.
假如由您来领导我们决战
Never morn the past, young warrior.
不必总是活在过去，年轻人
Thanks to you, our race survives.
感谢你，我们至少还都活着
You were our leader, Sentinel.
你是我们的领袖 御天敌
It is your right, to lead us again.
你可以再次领导我们
In a world I do not know.
在这个未知的世界上
I am no longer your teacher, Optimus.
我已不再是你的老师，柱子
You are mine.
你就代表我吧
We've got to break this case down.
我们必须中止这种情况了
What we have here is an astronaut epidemic.
我们这里有宇航员的传染病
M.I.A., dead, died in a car accident, killed, D.O.A., car death.
失踪 死亡 死于车祸 被杀 DOA 车祸
It's like these guys can't die. They can fly into outer space.
如果这些家伙没有死 他们可以飞入太空
But they can't drive a car.
但他们不会驾驶车子
Procured your information, Witwicky.
提供你情报 维特维奇
Thank you, Bruce.
谢谢你 布鲁斯
Noo.
别关
You let me see one of them, one time.
让我看看其中的一个 一次就好
- Quick. - Very.
- 快点 - 就一下
Here's their reconnaissance order.
这是他们侦察的顺序
It say's NASA launched in 2009.
它说航天局于2009年启动
See, forensics show Wang may have messed with the code.
你看 证据显示王可能把代码搞乱
Preventing it from mapping the far side of the moon.
防止测绘出月球的另一面
Which is also the Dark side.
这也是黑暗的一面
Freaking awesome.
不同凡响
Painful trade us, intimidate us.
渗透我们 恐吓我们
...coerce us to do their dirty work.
...强迫我们做他们的肮脏的工作
And once they're done?
而一旦任务完成了
Dushhhh.
砰砰
The double tap cerebellum.
脑袋两颗子弹
So he was working for the Decepticons.
所以他为霸天虎工作
I don't think this is about the Decepticons.
我不认为跟霸天虎有关
They're looking for something on the moon.
他们在寻找月球上的某个东西
I think it's about something...
我认为这跟某种东西有关...
...they wanted to hide.
...他们想隐藏起来
Come to daddy.
来见识见识爷的武艺
Come on, fall down.
来吧  下来
Did you eat a lot of paint chips when you were a kid?
当你是孩子时 吃了很多油漆晶片吧
Hah, like it.
哈 喜欢吗
I'll teach you...
（我会教你...）
Sir.
这位爷
Having a pretty high level alien Intel confab here.
我们正在做一个高度机密的外星人调查
That I don't think you're cleared for.
我想你是不是该消失了
- Errand boy. - Yeah, you're right.
- 跑腿的  - 是啊 你说的对
- It's a bitchin' robot. - At least have a go, sir.
- 真是个不错的机器人 - 你得闪了，先生
Thank you so much for this.
非常感谢你
Better go, Bruce.
最好快走 布鲁斯
Hey, I'm smokin' over here.
嘿 我在这里快冒烟了
Now with the missing Russian cosmonauts.
现在俄罗斯宇航员失踪
Turns out the soviets cancelled a manned mission to the moon.
苏联取消载人登月计划 本来预定
The moon, in 1972.
在1972年就到月亮上去
When 200 cosmonauts went into hiding in America.
大概有200个宇航员藏在美国
And I just found them, aaaah.
而我刚刚发现了他们，哈
You're a genuis, Brains.
你真是个天才 小诸葛
Oh that was smooth, Bumble Bee.
哦 悠着点 大黄蜂
Missed it by that much.
（我闯祸了）
Hi.
嗨
Would somebody tell me what the hell's going on?
能告诉我这他妈是怎么回事？
Who are you?
你是谁
- Who are you? - Who am I?
- 你又是谁？  - 我是谁？
Who is that? Dutch, frisk her.
那是谁 Dutch 搜身
- Certainly. - Here, no.
- 没问题  - 这，不
Dutch, um...
Dutch 嗯...
Don't touch me.
别碰我
- I'm not going to...  - Sam?
- 我不会... - Sam？
Angel.
亲爱的
Uh, I was working.
嗯 我正在工作
I'm sorry about this.
我对此感到抱歉
Great, we're homeless.
太好了 我们无家可归了
She lives here?
她住在这？
Wow!
哇！
You had your chance to frisk her.
你有机会替她搜身
I have a girl friend.
我有个女朋友
Really, what's her name?
真的 她叫什么名字
Innn...dia.
印...蒂亚
We're suppose to be at Dylan party, remember?
我们现在要去参加Dylan的派对 记得吗
I do remember, but you know, my friends,
我记得 但你知道 我的朋友
...they need me. I have to be here right now.
...他们需要我 我现在得留下
And what, the Autobots and the military they can't handle this on their own.
为什么 汽车人还有军队不能自己处理吗
You know what I liked about your war stories, Sam?
你知道为什么我喜欢你的那些故事吗 Sam
It's that they were stories.
那是他们的故事
They were in the past.
但这些已经过去了
Look, I know you're thinking about your brother.
听着 我知道你想念你兄弟
Okay, and you're thinking about your family.
你也想念着你的家人
And it's not that situation.
但是它不是这种情况
- No? - No.
- 不是？ - 不是
Why not?
为什么不是
Why isn't it, Sam?
为什么不是 Sam
You think we'd rather has his medals, or we'd rather have him?
你觉得我喜欢他的勋章还是喜欢他的人？
I hear you, I get it.
如你所愿 这是我的
Where are you taking my bunny, stop.
你要把我的幸运兔拿哪去 停下
Just stop for a second.
只要停一秒钟
You think I could sleep last night?
你以为我昨晚还睡得着
I mean it hit me. No, Sam want's the big danger.
这事刺激我 不 Sam他不会去冒险的
He doesn't know who he is without it.
他们都不知道对手是谁
I just wanna matter.
我只是在乎这些
You matter to me.
谁在乎我？
I know you're worried, I know you're worried.
我知道你担心 我知道你担心
But I promise you I can, I can handle this.
但我答应你 我可以处理这事的
Can you, you can promise it?
你可以 你能保证吗
I promise.
我保证
Sam, I don't want to loose you, and I know where this leads.
Sam 我不想失去你 而我知道这点
I'm not ready for this.
这一点我还没有准备好
Are you coming with me?
你要跟我来吗
I can't.
我不能
Okay.
好吧
Hey.
嘿
Here's your foot.
这是你的脚
A warrior's path is a solitary one.
战士的路途总是孤独的
How the hell does she afford that car?
天啊 她是如何负担得起这辆车
- Her boss. - Rich bastards.
- 她的老板 - 有钱的势利小人
I used to hate them.
以前我恨他们
But now it's...
但现在...
Going to a gang on a hunt for two Russian Cosmonauts.
现在要做的就是去追捕两名俄罗斯宇航员
Nothing like driving in a Maybach, huh?
没有比开着迈巴赫更爽 是吧
Germans know how to make cars, let me tell ya.
德国人知道如何制造车子 让我告诉你
My Dutch man. Former NSA, Cyber sleuth extraordinaire.
Dutch 前美国国家安全局 出色的网络黑客
Tracked them down, here.
记录下来 这里
So these cosmonauts wanted to hide. Why?
这些宇航员想躲起来 为什么呢
Bingo, I got a match.
好极了 找到目标
You're a German Shepard, Dutch.
你是简直就是只德国牧羊犬 Dutch
The thing about Russians is...
关于俄国佬...
...they never like to talk.
他们从来不善于交谈
It's going to take a little of the international language.
这将需要些国际语言
- Dos vedanya. - That means goodbye.
- 你知道我意味着什么 -这意味着再见
Who's to get revolution.
谁赢得了革命
A famous, I have no idea.
反正是名人 我不知道
Dutch.
Dutch
Give me something tough.
给我些难一点的
- Baryshnikov. - We do speak English.
- 巴雷什尼科夫 - 我们会讲英语
Dutch, you suck.
Dutch 你太烂了
It's a Cyrillic, alphabet.
这是一个字母  字母
It's like all the buttons you never push on a calculator.
这像一堆拼音 你还没输入电脑而已
I don't suck.
我不烂
Agent Seymour Simmons, CETI. Formerly Seta.
西摩西蒙斯特工 CETI 前情报员
We know who you are.
我们知道你是谁
Cosmonaut chicks.
宇航员chicks
So what?
那又怎样
You were suppose to travel to the Dark side of the moon, then....
你们曾想探索月亮黑暗一面 然而..
It all got shut down.
这一切都停滞了
The question is.
问题是
Why?
为什么呢
Can my child smoke in here?
我的孩子能在这里抽烟吗
Okay, all right. Okay!
好了 没事 好吧
- Yeah, shoot me. - Who was this delish, huh?
- 是啊 开枪啊  - 这个家伙是谁
I'm only the driver in my country are you?
我只是司机而已 你呢
You are beautiful.
你真美
Has anyone told you, you're beautiful?
有没有人说你很漂亮
'Cause she's a beautiful woman.
因为她是一个美丽的女人
Whoa, hey!
哇 嘿
Dutch, back in the cage.
Dutch 退到包厢
Control your boy, please control your boy.
控制你的男孩 请控制好你的人
Dutch, stop!
Dutch 停下来
I'm so sorry. That is the old me.
我很抱歉 这是以前的我
Okay, let's everybody just calm down.
好吧 让我们冷静下来
Let's lower the heat, lower the guns. Just relax.
让我们消消火气 放下枪  放轻松
World War 2 is over.
第二次世界大战已经结束了
You're about to see one of the biggest soviet secrets.
你将看到苏联一个最大的秘密
America first to send men to the moon.
美国最先送人上到月球
But U.S.S.R. first to send camera.
但苏联先送相机上去
In 1969 our Lunar 3.
1969年我们的农历3月
take picture of the Dark,
the shadow side.
拍摄到月亮黑暗一面的图片
See's nothing.
没见到什么
- But in 1963 Lunar 4 sees.. - ... strange rocks.
- 但在1963年农历4月看到.. - ...奇怪的岩石
- Yeah. - Around the ship.
- 是啊 - 围绕着飞船
Hundreds of them.
它们数以百计
Here, show picture.
照片在这里
With some, drag marks.
有些 拖痕
I've seen these, these aren't rocks.
我已经看了这些 这些不是岩石
These are pillars.
这些是能源棒
Alien pillars for a space bridge.
外星能源棒可以用来制造太空桥
We know about them because the Autobots have five of these.
我们知道是因为我们见过汽车人有五个这些东西
The decepticons must have raided the ship before Apollo 11 ever got there.
霸天虎在阿波罗 11号到那里前 一定有搜查过
Took the pillars and hid them.
拿走那些能源棒并藏了起来
Well that doesn't make sense. The Decepticons have the ship.
这说不通啊 霸天虎拥有飞船
They have all those pillars. Why would they leave several...
并且早就得到了能源棒为什么会离开...
... of these if he's the only one that can use them?
...他说过 他是唯一一个可以控制技术的人
Unless...
所以...
He's the one thing they still need.
这个人就是他们所需要的关键
We got to meet up with Sentinel.
我们必须找到御天敌
Rendezvous with him, and keep him safe.
与他会合 并保护他的安全
Mearing, I just picked up Sentinel, Optimus is10 minutes behind.
梅琳 我10分钟后与御天敌和擎天柱会合
We're coming in fast, now.
我们现在马上就到
Mr. Witwicky I thought I made it clear to you, that I did not want you calling this phone.
维特维奇先生 我要跟你说清楚 你不能打这个电话
Listen, the whole thing has been a set up since the beginning.
听着 这一切从一开始这就是个陷阱
Decepticons wanted Optimus to find Sentinel,
霸天虎想要让擎天柱找到御天敌
because only Optimus could revive him.
因为只有擎天柱可以使他苏醒
But we have the space bridge.
但我们还有太空桥
Mearing, you have five pillars.
你只不过是有5支能源棒
I just learned that they have hundreds.
他们却有好几百个
You're doing exactly what they wanted you to do.
你要做的正是他们想要你做的
What do I need to say to you.
我为什么要跟你说
The Decepticons are coming for Sentinel Prime.
霸天虎是为御天敌而来的
We're going to NEST.
我们到NEST去
We have an Energon alert.
危机警报
Energon reading detected on .....
数据检测启动....
Currently tracking.
正在检测来源
Three black suburban.
是那三辆SUV
B, you gotta get Sentinel out of here, you got to floor it.
大黄蜂 你得带御天敌离开这里 藏起来
Oh man, oh I'm fine.
噢 人 哦 我没事
Watch out, watch out.
小心 小心
Gotcha.
逮到了
Shoot him, shoot him!
射他 打他
Shoot him, B.
干死他们 大黄
B, you gotta move.
Faster, faster B, go!
大黄 你动作得快点 快 大黄 走
Wipeout.
我擦
Come on, back to NEST.
来吧 回NEST去
Dino, I got him.
DINO，交给我
Is there a problem?
有问题吗
Whoa, little Mexican stand-off we got here.
哇 小墨西哥佬闪开 我们在这呢
Weapons down.
放下武器
And we'll let you escape with your dignity.
我们来场有尊严的决斗
Drop them.
扔掉
That's good.
这就对了
Ironhide,  watch out.
铁皮 当心
Ironhide, catch.
铁皮 接住
Behind you.
小心背后
Decepticon punk.
霸天虎 废物！
Class dismissed.
解散
- Inside, let's go. - Move.
- 快进去 我们走吧  - 快点
Quick, move it.
快 快点
- Lennox. - Go, go, go, go.
- 伦诺克斯  - 快 快 快 快
We got decepticons everywhere.
霸天虎到处都是
I got my whole team deployed looking for them.
我得部署全部人马寻找他们
Ironhide!
铁皮
Protect Sentinel, get him locked up inside.
保护御天敌 让他锁在里面
Consider it done.
交给我
You gotta guard him, because he's the key to the whole thing.
你要保护他 因为他是一切的关键
Indeed I am.
我当然是
What you must realized, my Autobot brothers.
你们还没搞明白 我的汽车人兄弟们
Is we were never going to win the war.
这场战争我们永远无法获胜
For the sake of our planets survival.
为了拯救星球
A deal had to be made.
我们必须达成一个交易
With Megatron.
和威震天
Get back!
退后
What have you done?
你在做什么
I hereby discharge you from duty.
我是在帮你从使命中解脱
- B! - Get back.
- 大黄  - 退后
Bring all the NEST forces back to the base.
叫所有人队回基地
Come on, move.
来吧 快走
Get them in, get them here. We don't have enough men.
让他们进去 要他们在这里 我们没有足够的人手
Do not engage Sentinel.
不要与御天敌交战
Just go to the back gate.
到后门就好
Director, down.
主任 趴下
Let's slide, let's slide
让我们过 让我们过
Go, follow me.
走 跟我走
Start firing.
开始射击
- Wait don't. - Get out.
- 等等 不要 - 滚开
Hey, Sentinel.
嘿 御天敌
What is going on?
这是怎么回事
What do you think you're doing?
你到底在干什么
I am a Prime.
我是个元老
I do not take orders from you.
没有人可以命令我
Director Mearing come on. We can't fight him, let's go.
梅琳主任 来吧 我们打不过它 走吧
- We have to go. - Now.
- 我们得走了 - 现在
Return what belongs to me.
把我的东西还给我
Oh, my god.
哦 天啊
Everybody out, everybody out.
大家都出来 大家出来
Everybody stay calm.
大家保持冷静
Yeah take a look, Optimus.
是啊 看看 擎天柱
This is all on you.
这都是你招来的
The Sentinel hit the vault.
御天敌攻击了保险库
Took the pillars.
拿走了能源棒
Come on, let's go.
来吧 我们走
All right, notify the 101st airborne.
好了 通知第101空降支援
We need to hunt this thing down.
我们需要解决这件事情
Carly.
Carly
Hot for a little camp fire.
用营火热了一下
- Smores. - Aw.
- 香吧  - 喔
Isn't this great, we are really living off the land.
很棒吧 我们真的生活在天堂
Ma, Dad. Have you guys seen Carly come home yet?
妈爸 你们有看到Carly回家了吗
Excuse me, can you knock please.
你为什么不敲门
This is our bedroom.
这是我们的卧室
Why wouldn't she be at home?
她为什么不在家里
We had a fight, and....
我们吵了一架 然后...
We might have broken up, or be on a break. I don't really know.
我们可能分手了 也许暂时 我真不知道
- What!?.. Noo. - Look, I can't talk about it.
- 什么 不  - 听着 我没空谈这些
- You gotta be kidding me. - I can't go into details now, Mom.I have to find her.
- 你一定是跟我开玩笑的 - 我现在无法详述 妈妈 我必须找到她
Sam, we're having a family meeting.
Sam 我们有个家庭会议
Family meeting.
家庭会议
You may not know this. But your father and I were not always this perfectly happy.
你可能不知道 但是你父亲与我并不是总这样快乐
You know there was a time in our marriage when I thought,
你知道有段时间我以为我们的婚姻
"This is not going to work out."
“这是行不通的”
- Can you please hurry up. - I'm just hope you ...
- 请你快点好吗 - 我只是希望你...
- .. just understand that you... - She's damaging me.
- 了解你自己...  - 她甩了我
...break up with one world class high.
...整个世界都崩溃了
- No, stop, stop, okay. - Yeah.
- 不 停 停 好不好  - 是啊
She dumped me, I moved to something better.
她甩了我 我最好走开
- That's it, I'm a happier person. - It's not going to be as beautiful...
- 就这样 我是一个快乐的人 - 那不会更美好...
- Lose her, why did you lose her? - Help me.
- 失去她 为什么你失去她  - 救命
- They had an argument. - We had a fight.
- 他们起了争执  - 我们吵了一架
Okay, but you're not going to get a third one.
好吧 但是你可不能找小三
I mean unless you have like a big...
我是说 除非你有一个这样大...
什么 老妈
- ...
- What the, mom!
- Mom, mom, don't want to talk about it. - I mean you just don't know.
- 老妈 老妈 别说了  - 我是说你不知道
- Just don't want to talk. - You need a book.
- 就不要再说了  - 你需要一本书
- You'll always wrong.  - Hey,
- 你永远是错的  - 嘿
- Get used to it. -Okay, this you gotta read this.
- 必须习惯 - 好吧 你得看这一本
She comes first, there's some killer...
“她是第一个” 有一些杀手...
- ...shit in here. - No, No, No.
- 就在这里 - 不 不
- Ah, lets get this. - No, no.
- 啊 来吧  - 不 不
- No, no.  - Sit down. Sit down!
- 不 不  - 坐下 坐下
Back me up.
支持我
Happy wife, happy life.
老婆高兴, 人生如意
- Yeah. - unhappy wife
- 是啊  - 老婆不高兴
Stone cold misery for the rest of your...
让你的结果悲惨凄凉...
- Stop. - It's true.
- 住嘴  - 这是真的
All I'm saying is.
我所要说的是
Do you love this girl?
你爱这个女孩吗
She's the one.
她是我的唯一
Then you gotta go get her.
那么去追她
I mean, your dad and I, when we had troubles.
我的意思是 你爸和我 当我们遇到问题时
He moved heaven and earth to find me.
他总是千方百计找到我
Would he, say what you said.
然后他会  说你所说的话
Say it.
说出来
I would follow you to the end of time.
我会陪你到地老天荒
- Does that suck or what? - No.
- 这是否很变态 还是什么  - 不
Bad syfy dope.
一塌糊涂
I want you guys to get as far away from here as you can.
我希望你们能尽可能远离这里
You understand?
明白吗
I love you.
我爱你们
Oh, my master.
哦，我的老大
Such a brilliant scheme.
这个计划真是天衣无缝
So, when Sentinel left Cybertron,
这么说来，御天敌离开赛博坦的时候
...it was to defect.
...就已经叛变了？
He was meant to rendezvous with me here on Earth,
他是为了到地球与我碰头
before fate waylaid us both.
但命运却把我们俩都捉弄了一翻
The only way to revive him,
只有这样才能复活他
...we needed Prime and his matrix.
...用擎天柱和他的领导模块
Excellent strategy.
高！实在是高！
So he is now your partner, master.
那现在他是我们一伙的了，老大
He is my greatest triumph.
他是我们通向胜利的基石！
So impressive.
佩服！
Commencing transport.
开始传输
Stop!No, no, no Sentinel!
住手！不，不，不，御天敌
Forgive me.
原谅我
Here we are.
寡人在此
Fight us now.
霸天虎们出击
Autobots, retreat.
汽车人，快撤退
Why Sentinel, why?
为什么 御天敌 这是为什么？
For Cybertron.
一切为了赛博坦
For our home.
为了我们的家园
What war destroyed, we can rebuild.
毁于战火的 我们可以重建
But only if we join with the Decepticons.
但只有我们加入霸天虎
No, it's not the only way.
不 这不是唯一的方法
This is our home.
这里就我们的家园
We must defend the humans.
我们必须保卫人类
So lost you are, Optimus.
你错了，柱子
On Cybertron we were Gods.
在赛博坦，我们被敬为神
And here they call us machines.
在这里，他们却称我们是机器
Let the humans serve us.
让人类为我们服务
Or perish.
或者灭亡
You're lucky I didn't kill you.
你很幸运 我没有杀了你
In time, you'll see.
迟早 你会看到的
It's not over.
这不算完
And if I were him,
如果我是他
...I wouldn't let you out of my sight for one second.
...我不会让你离开我的视线一秒钟
It's funny I was just thinking on the way over here,
很有趣 我在到这里的途中想着
I really could use some advice from Dylan.
我真的需要听从Dylan的意见
- And there he is. Can I speak to you? - Welcome.
- 他在这里 我可以跟谈谈么？ - 欢迎
Please sit down, have a drink.
请坐下 喝一杯
You know what, I don't need a drink.
你知道吗 我不需要喝一杯
Or a car, or a job.
关于汽车，或者工作
I just need to speak to my girlfriend alone.
我只想跟我的女朋友单独谈话
Is that okay with you, Mr. Inappropriate?
木关系啊 不适当先生
Excuse me.
打扰
- What's going on? - I'll tell you outside.
- 怎么回事？ - 我到外面告诉你
I really think I can help you, Sam.
我真的希望可以帮助你，Sam
I remember a talk I had with my dad once, about tough choices.
我记得曾与我爸谈过关于艰难的抉择
Now's not the time, I'll set something up, though.
现在不是时候 我设置些东西了
Course that was way back when my dad's firm was in charge
当然说回来 我父亲的公司是负责
of budget review and accounting for NASA.
对美国太空总署预算的审查
You see the thing that he taught me was...
你看到的东西是他教我的...
When it's not your war,
当它不是你的战争
you join the side that's going to win.
你要加入会赢的一方
To direct, or was it just me?
直说 还是它刚好是我
Certainly not you, sir.
当然不是你 先生
You're mine.
你是我的
Noooo!
不
- Get help. Someone get help. - Sam, I cant get out.
- 救命 来人啊 - Sam,我出不来
- Goodnight - Goodnight Mr. Dylan.
- 晚安  -晚安 Dylan先生
Sam, get me out of here.
Sam,带我离开这里
Help.
救命
Get help.
He's young, live and learn.
他还年轻，富有活力 需要去学习
- Get me out.- Goodnight.
- 让我出来 - 晚安
This was a fun night.
这是个有趣的夜晚
You really think you're the first man ever asked to join a noble alien cause?
你真的以为只有你是唯一接触过外星人的人
Who are you?
你是谁
You know why we've not been back to the moon since 1972?
你知道为什么自1972年后我们再没有重返月球吗
Because these two?
就因为这两货？
They came to my dad and they told him to do some creative accounting.
他们来找我老爸 告诉他如何做一些有创意的计划
Make it way to expensive to ever go back.
让重返月球变得很昂贵
So he and others, shut down the American and Russian space programs.
所以是他和其他人让美国和俄罗斯的太空计划停止
And they've been our clients ever since.
他们至今一直都是我们的客户
You helped to kill people?
你帮他们杀人？
You think they give you a choice?
你认为他们会给你选择？
Besides, it's not like I personally participated.
此外 我不须亲自参加会议
I am a liaison.
我是个纽带
I liaise.
我负责联络
It's hostile takeover time, Sam.
该是收掉敌意的时候了，Sam
Sam!
Let her go.
放开她
Sam.
I've had my eye on you for years, Sam.
我已经注意你很多年了，Sam
You're the one spy I've never been able to provide as the one close to the Autobots.
没有任何间谍像你，能让我更接近汽车人
Sam, don't do what he wants.
Sam,不要听他的
Yes he will.
会 他会的
They all do.
最终他们都会做
They all say, murder. You understand me.
他们都说，谋杀 你知道我的意思
The time it takes you to blink, they will do it to her, and they will do it to me.
一眨眼的功夫 他们就能做掉她 为了我
So  you show a little respect.
所以你要表现尊重一点
When someone offers you a job.
特别是当有人给你一份工作时
Wrist.
手腕
You are to track down, Optimus Prime.
你要去追查擎天柱
Because you're the one human he trusts.
因为你是他信任的人类
You will ask one question.
你要问他一个问题
How does he intend to fight back?
他打算怎么反击
Strategies, tactics, everything.
战略 战术 所有的
Has a nasty little bite, doesn't it.
有些讨厌的刺痛 不是吗
It's very high tech.
这是非常高科技
It lets us see what you see, hear what you hear.
让我们看到你所看到 听到你所听到的
And it attacks your nervous system.
它会刺激你的神经系统
So if you so much as try and signal.
如果你想尝试传递讯息时
I know what to tell you, Sam.
我知道该怎么告诉你，Sam
Relationships have consequences.
有因必有果
I am here because my father, she is here because of you.
我在这里是因为我老爸 她是在这里是因为你
Stop! Stop, stop...stop.
住手 住手 住手...
Soundwave, if you please.
声波  请你松开
Sam.
Do your job.
去做事
She'll be safe.I give you my word.
她就会安全 我给你挂保证
I'll kill you.
我会杀了你
You have my word.
我给你挂保证
Combatant commands are now at Defcom 1.
作战命令 现在是Defcom 1
Approximately 200 Decepticons are in hiding.
大约有200个霸天虎是掩藏的
Energon detectors have been triggered as far away as South America and China.
所有探测器被启动远至南美和中国
The U.N. just received an encrypted audio file.
联合国安理会刚收到加密的音频文件
They say it's from the leaders of the Autobots.
他们说是汽车人的领袖送来的
Defenders of Earth.
捍卫地球
We have come for your natural resources.
我们来为了你们的自然资源
To rebuild our damaged planet.
来重建我们毁损的星球
When we have transported all we needed.
当我们传运完所有我们需要的
We will leave your world in peace.
我们会和平的离开你们的世界
For such peace to exist.
为了让这和平存在
You must immediately exile the Autobot rebels you have harbored.
你们必须立即驱逐所包庇的汽车人叛军
Non negotiable.
没有谈判
Renounce the rebels.
流放叛军
We await your reply.
我们等待你们的答覆
We'll debrief you in transit.
我们会在运输途中听取报告
Yeah I really don't see how I can be of any help.
我实在看不出我可以帮助什么
I mean you guys seem pretty busy.
我的意思是你们看上去都很忙
We can just do this another time, I think.
我想我们可以再找时间
I have underestimated you at every turn.
我完全低估了你的一切
You..ha...what?
你..哈...什么？
You warned us that they were using humans.
你警告过我们他们利用人类
And you knew that Sentinel was the key.
你还知道御天敌是关键
Director.
主任
Oh, who am I? Hey, you're the expert.
哦，我算那棵葱？嘿 你是专家
I'm just a walking security leak.
我只不过是个传话的
Are you all right?
你没事吧
Yes.
是的
- No you're not, you're sweating. - No, I'm fine.
- 不 你没有 你在出汗 - 不 我很好
I'm fine. I'm sweating because I'm nervous.
我很好 我大汗淋漓因为我紧张
I'm nervous because you got me in here for this information, okay.
我很紧张是因为你有我要的信息 行了吧
I'm a twitter junkie, I blog everything, I can't keep secrets.
我是个大嘴巴 我爆料一切 我不能守密
- Oh you wouldn't dare. - That's the truth, I'm telling you.
- 哦 你不敢 - 这是事实，我要让你知道
- You wouldn't dare.- Director I got a call for you at 15.
- 你不敢 - 主任 我接到一个你的电话 在15线
What are you doing?
你想干什么？
Nothing, what are you doing?
没事，你在干什么？
Get away from me.
滚开
It's been a remarkable series of events today at the Capitol.
今天在国会大厦有值得注意的事件
Just moments ago legislation was passed to exile the Autobots from American shores.
不久前通过条例 美国政府和国会议员同意将汽车人流放
The U.S. military alliance with them is officially over.
美国与他们的军事同盟正式结束
- The words of the house and the...- Yeah.
- 政府的发言和... - 是啊
..authority leaders responds to today's resolution.
权威的领导人回应今天的决议
- What? - We cannot in good conscious invite...
- 什么？- 我们不能拒绝善意的条件....
They can't do this, you gotta tell them they can't do that.
他们不能这么做 你得告诉他们 他们不能这样做
Okay, it's official, it's a go people!
好吧 这是官方的 该走了
These are our allies. The Autobot's fought for us, they fought with us.
他们都是我们的盟友 汽车人为我们而战
And where are we now?
而我们现在在哪里
Facing an enemy invasion.
面对敌人的入侵
With an enemy that has the means to deploy countless more.
针对敌情需要有各种应对措施
If there's more you know?
如果你有更多知道的
Anything at all about the enemies intentions.
任何有关敌人的意图
Now's the time to tell.
现在就该说了
Autobots have no way of leaving this planet.
汽车人没有办法离开这个星球
That is where you're wrong.
这你就想错了
It's name is the Xanthium.
这是苍耳号
It bought the second wave of Autobots.
它带来了第二次波的汽车人
And it's been under NASA's care and study ever since.
此后一直由美国宇航局负责研究和管理
We've linked it with a decommissioned shuttle,
我们已经将它绑定在一架航天飞机上
to maintain military control until they're gone.
并用军事设施监督他们，直到他们离开
Gonna be 10,000 pounds of torque on that
那玩意有10,000磅的扭力
on this cheaper Cheep-oh, not my thing.
这是廉价货，不关我的事
You damage this delays all me mates.
你毁坏这个会拖我们大家后腿
That's your wreckers.
这就是你的雷霆小队
They take care of the Xanthium.
他们在整修苍耳号
We don't let them off the base much, because they're assholes.
我们不会让他们离开基地太远，因为他们都是混蛋
You gotta pull that you Nancy wanker.
你得拉这个，灌铅脚
It's torqued to kill them.
它的扭力会杀了他们
Calm down.
冷静点
- Epps.- You are ridiculous, that's you.
- Epps.- 你真逗，居然是你
Hello, man.
你好 伙计
I'm retired from the air force.
我从空军退役了
Can you let my hand go?
能让我的手过去吗
What the hell was that?
这他妈是什么意思？
I went on to just consult and run interference for them.
现在我只就是一个执行协调顾问
No more combat or alien shooting at my ass.
再也没有战斗或外星人射我的屁股了
I got a dream job.
我有一个理想的工作
Keeping the Autobots here.
驱逐汽车人
Do you believe this is happening?
你能相信这是什么狗屁？
Where do you think is taking them?
你认为哪里能接受他们
Any planet but here.
任何星球，除了这里
I want to talk to whoever's in charge here.
我要跟这里的主管说话
Well, well, well.
我了个擦
Charlotte Mearing.
夏洛特梅琳
Agent Simmons
西蒙斯特工
Former Agent Simmons, so.
前 西蒙斯特工
I see you survived Washington.
我看你在华盛顿挺活跃
Washington, Egypt, heartbreak.
华盛顿 埃及 让人心碎
I survived, I will survive.
我活了下来 我会继续生存下去
They're bringing everybody in, kid.
他们把每个人都带进去了 孩子
Putting all the Intel on the table.
把所有的英特尔放在桌子上
And if you think that putting 9 Autobots,
你认为把九个汽车人驱逐出境
is going to solve a damn thing.
能够解决什么
It's out of my hands.
不是我负责的
Moving up in the world, huh?
赶出地球 是吧
Your booty looks excellent.
你的身段看来还不错嘛
You ever say word to anyone about what happened that night in Quantico.
在匡蒂科当晚发生了什么事 你怎么没有向任何人提起过
I'll cut your heart out.
我把你的心砍掉了
You already did.
你已经做到了
Sammy, listen to me.
Sammy, 听我说
- Don't let them exile us.- Don't let them take us, Sam.
- 不要让他们流放我们 - 不要让他们放弃我们 Sam
It's a decepticon trap.
这是霸天虎的圈套
Checked the nitrogen, we're booking out o' here.
检查氮气的状态。让我们离开这
Optimus.
擎天柱
What your leaders say is true.
你们的领导人说的是事实
This was all my fault.
这全都是我的错
I told them whom to trust.
我告诉他们 谁值得信任
I was so wrong.
我是真的错了
It doesn't make your fault,it makes you human for a change.
它不是你的错，犯错是人之常情
Remember this.
记住这一点
You may loose your faith in us.
你可能会失去对我们的信任
But never in yourselves.
但绝不要对自己失去信心
I need to know how you're going to fight back.
我需要知道你如何反击
I know there's a strategy.
我知道这是你的想法
I know you're coming back with reinforcements.
我知道你将带援军回来
Something, I know there's a plan.
等等，你肯定有计划
You can tell me, no other human will ever know.
你可以告诉我，我可以保密
There is no plan.
我们并没有计划
We just do what they want, how are we going to live with ourselves?
我们只是做他们想要的，我们该如何面对自我
You are my friend, Sam.
你是我的朋友, Sam
You always will be.
你永远都是
But your leaders have spoken.
但这是你的领导决定
From here.
从现在开始
The fight will be your own.
你们要孤军作战
Make it short.
长话短说
We're loading up.
我们准备离开
All right, hustle up!
好吧 那就挤上去
When we do whatever we can.
（我们已尽竭尽所能）
Make it like a bow.
（就像强弩之末）
You will always be, my friend.
（你是我永远永远的朋友）
Sam.
（Sam)
I gotta be going on.
（我得上路了）
Years from now, they're gonna ask us.
多年以后当他们问起
Where were you when the took over the planet?
地球被侵占时你们在做什么
We're gonna say.
而我们却说
We just stood by and watched.
我们在袖手旁观
You should really look at this as a partnership.
你应该把它看成一种合作伙伴关系
You have to stand on the side of progress if you want to be a part of history.
你必须站站到进步的一面，如果你想载入史册
Go launch in..5...4...3..2
进入发射倒数5... 4... 3... 2
1...zero.
1...0
- The word is, you got it.- I always get what I want, Sam.
- 这句话是 你得逞了 - 我总是得到我想要的, Sam
We just needed to be sure.
我需要确定
Sure of what?
确定什么
That they would to without a fight.
他们会死光光
- Say again? - Detecting a foreign object.
- 再说一遍 - 侦测到不明飞行物
We all work for the Decepticons now.
现在我们全都为霸天虎工作
Chicago, Illinois
伊利诺州 芝加哥市
I need your help to track a phone call.
我需要你的帮助 连系个电话
It's a man on this phone, he's the head of the human operation.
手机上的家伙 他是带头的，出卖整个人类
And he's holding Carly hostage.
还控制Carly当人质
Sit down, don't move.
坐下 不要动
I'm watching him drive up right now.
我看着他正在出来
The call was placed in-route.
该电话有路由装置
I'm hacking into the Phones camera right now.
我正黑他手机的相机
There that's is, that's a live stream from the camera.
那里就是 这是摄影头的即时影像
Someplace, hold on I can triangulate this.
某个地方 等等我可以测出来
Okay, it's Chicago cell site.
好的 是芝加哥的基地台
There, I got it. Trump tower, Chicago, lower penthouse.
在那里，找到了  是特朗普大厦，芝加哥，低楼层
We're on.
我们出发
- I'm going.- You're sure.
- 我要去 - 你确定
Thanks a lot for trying to help me, I can be there in 15 hours.
感谢你的帮助 我15小时就可以到那里
You're not going alone.
你不会只有一人的
Still got my NEST friends out there.
我还有NEST的朋友在那里
We'll round them up, find your girlfriend and bring this guy in.
我们会全面集合起来找到你的女朋友 把这个家伙解决
Why are you helping me?
你为什么要帮助我
'Cause that asshole killed my friends, too.
因为那个混蛋也杀害了我的朋友
They said they were here for our resources.
他们说 在这里是为了我们的资源
To rebuild their planet.
用以重建他们自己的星球
Yes, really one resource in particular.
是的 这真是一个特殊的资源
One unique to our planet.
一种我们星球独有资源
Us.
就是我们
You're very smart.
你真聪明，亲
You see they can't rebuild without a slave labor force.
你知道他们，没有劳动力是无法进行重建的
How many rocks up there in the universe offer 6 billion workers?
如何动用6亿工人在宇宙中搬石头？
What are you talking about?
说啥呢
We can't transport people.
我们不会传输人
They're not shipping people.
他们不运送人类
They're shipping their planet here.
他们运送他们的星球
Oh, my God.
哦 天啊
What's Sentinel doing here?
御天敌在做什么
Watch.
注意看
They're spreading 100's of pillars around the globe right now.
他们现在要散布100多个能源棒到世界各地
In just a few hours.
在短短几个小时
They're going to launch them into orbit.
他们就可以推出它们送入轨道
And bring Cybertron into our atmosphere.
把赛博坦传送至我们的大气层
The red one there, controls the rest.
那个红的控制着运转
He triggers that, it starts the whole thing.
它是触发器，它启动整个系统
Be gone insect operative, your work is done.
可以走了，蛀虫， 你的工作完成了
- Your Excellency.- You're such a dick.
-是阁下  -尼玛
- You want this to happen?- I want to survive, I want 40 more years.
- 你竟要让这种事情发生 - 我要生存 我还想要享受40多年
You  think I asked for this?
你觉得这只是我的立场
I inherited a client.
我还承诺了我的客户们
Yeah, and when Cybertron's here and we're all their slaves.
是啊 当赛博坦到了我们就都成奴隶了
I guess they'll still need a human leader.
不过我想他们仍然需要一个人类当主子
Get this straight, you want to survive you listen to me.
就这样，想活命就得听我的
It is time for the slaves of earth to recognize their masters.
是时候让地球的奴隶见识下自己的主人
Seal off the city.
封锁城市
Get the dogs out of here now, get them in the back.
把狗带离这里 让他们在后面
I guess they didn't tell you about this part, did they.
我猜他们没有告诉你这部分 有吗
You think I'm at every meeting?
你以为每次开会都有我
They promised here.
他们答应了
They said it was hell.
他们说 这是地狱
Let's roll.
我们走
Don't have a signal reading.
还没有任何信号
It's not working.
它不能用
You were standing in the wake of devastation
当你站在灾难后的遗迹前
You were waiting on the edge of the unknown
当你等待着不可预测的变化
With the cataclysm raining down
此时灾难即将瓢泼而至
Insides crying "save me now"
你的内心哭喊着“拯救我”
You were there impossibly alone
却无法忽视万分孤单的处境
Move back.
转回去
There's a ring of alien ships around Chicago.
有一圈外星太空船围绕芝加哥
Our high range bombers were just knocked out of the sky.
我们的远程轰炸机全军覆没
They can't get through enemy air defenses over the city.
他们无法通过敌人的防空系统
Our satellites have been jammed. We have no way to monitor the enemies movement.
我们的卫星不能正常工作，根本没有机会来监视敌情
All NEST teams are on stand down.
所有NEST部队听命
Only have troops at air force base, move out.
只有空军部队留守，出发
10 minutes from the battle zone.
10分钟前来自前线
We have special forces trying to gain access to the city.
我们的特种部队试图进入到市区
An infantry is staging at the perimeter.
一个步兵团正抵达的边界
Excuse me, excuse me,it just doesn't make sense.
对不起 抱歉 它没有任何讯号
Can't we get any eyes in there at all?
我们没办法在那里得到任何影像吗
They keep shooting down our drones.
他们不断击落我们的无人飞机
They want us blind.
他们就要让我们抓瞎
But we do have a couple of mini-drones we're gonna try.
但我们有些小型无人飞机 我们要试试
-Well if we can man these UAV drones,
好吧 如果我们可以控制这些无人机
..can we try to redirect them toward,Trump Tower?
我们可以试着让他们改向 特朗普大厦
The kid, Witwicky was on his way to Chicago.
那孩子，维特维奇正赶去芝加哥
Set some point man human op is there.
在那里设置一些标记点
Before the Decepticons punks.
赶在混账霸天虎之前
Listen, if I know anything, I know this.
听着 如果我知道什么 我知道这个
That kid is an alien bad news magnet.
那家伙是外星人的卧底
My God.
我的天啊
We came here to find her in the middle of all that?
我们来这能找到她么，在市中心？
Are we really going out there, Epps?
我们真的要去那里，Epps?
I'm not going in there.
我不会去那里
No one's going in.
没有人会进去
I am.
我会
With or without you, I'll find her.
有没有你们，我都要去找她
You're gonna get yourself killed, Sam.
你要去寻死啊 Sam
Is that what you want?
这就是你想要的吗
Is that what you want.
You came all the way out here to get yourself killed.
你想尽办法到这里就是为了自己寻死？
Huh? Listen, to me what I'm saying.
嗯？听我说，我说
She's here because of me, do you understand?
她是因为我才被带到这里来的，明白吗？
Listen, if you go in this build.
听着，即使你进入大楼
That's if she's even still alive.
即使她还活着
There's no way you're going to be able to even reach her.
你甚至根本没有办法可以接近他
Well what would you suggest I do.
那你觉得我要怎么办
It's over.
结束了
I'm sorry, but it's over.
我很抱歉，但它结束了
No.
不
Woah, incoming!
哇，他们来了
We will kill them all.
我们要杀光他们
Wreckers, kill him.
雷霆小队，干掉他
This is going hurt.
这是相当的疼
必须的
Your leaders will now understand.
你们领导人现在应该明白了
Decepticons will never leave your planet alone.
霸天虎永远不会独自离开你们星球的
And we needed them to believe we had gone.
而我们必须让他们相信我们已经走了
For today, in the name of freedom.
今天，我们以自由为名
We take the battle to them.
向他们宣战！
I saw your ship blow up.
我看见你的太空船炸毁了
The ship, we were never in the ship.
太空船 我们从来没有在船上
We designed the damn thing, didn't we.
这破玩意就是我们设计的，有木有
We were hidden in the first booster rocket to separate.
我们隐藏在第一节火箭推进器被分离
Splashed down back in the Atlantic, just as planned.
按原定计划掉入大西洋
We ain't going no where.
我们不会去任何地方
Yeah, no ones exiling us.
是的 没有人放逐我们
The Autobots are staying right here.
汽车人整装待发
We're going to help you win this war.
我们来帮助你们赢得这场战争
They're surrounding the city to make a fortress.
他们摧毁了城市封锁信息
So that no one can see what they're up to inside.
因此 没有人可以看到他们里面搞什么
Our only chance is the element of surprise.
我们唯一的机会算是个惊喜
I think I know where to look.
我想我知道去哪里找到
Mini-drones on approach, Trump Tower.
小型无人飞机接近特朗普大厦上空
You're telling me, Sam's headed into that?
你告诉我 Sam深入到了里面
Poor kid.
可怜的孩子
Probably never got close.
也许从来没有靠近到过
Your gonna fly this thing, right?
你能飞的 对不对
What does, what is that, what is that?
是什么 那是什么 那是什么
So, so.
所以 所以
So you so, so can fly.
所以 你能飞
That feels terrible.
墨迹可不好
We're right behind ya.
我们做你的后盾
All right.
好吧
We're going in.
我们进去
The city's secure.
这座城市被封锁了
The humans cannot stop us.
人类无法阻挡我们
As the afternoon falls.
到下午的时候
The rest of the pillars will reach their launch position.
其余的能源棒会到达发射阵地
This is the victory I promised you so many years ago.
这是就是我多年前向你承诺的胜利
Where we rebuild Cybertron.
重建赛博坦的胜利
Together.
我们共同的胜利
I have gained to work with you.
我曾经承诺与你合作
That I planet may survive.
那是为了拯救赛星
I will never work for you.
我从来没有为你工作
And you would be wise to remember the difference.
你最好放聪明点区别这其中的差别
Oh, I'm so sick of this. I'm sick of waiting.
哦 我讨厌这些 我讨厌等待
Where is she?
她在哪儿
Where is she!?
You've got some balls.
你还真有种
No, Sam!
不, Sam！
Nooo!
不！
Carly!
Jump.
跳
B, fire.
大黄，开火
Help him, B.
救他 大黄
Autobots, they're alive.
是汽车人，他们还活着
- They're here, Autobots.- Decepticons defend the pillar.
- 汽车人就在这！ - 霸天虎 保卫能源棒
Release the bridges.
升起桥梁
Find them.
找到他们
Sam.
You found me.
你找到了我
I'd find you anywhere.
我会找到你的 无论在哪里
... let's go, let's go.
....走吧 我们走
Well you're crazy.
你疯了
Here's design, is that us?
这有个设备 是我们的吗
This thing is a military UAV drone.
这是军用无人机靶机
Check to see if it's still working.
检查看还能不能用
Yeah, it's still got power.
是的 它仍然有动力
Flight control, do you copy?
飞行控制中心 听到了吗
Can you rotate?
你能旋转吗
Can you do something?
你能做点什么吗
I think we got something.
我想我们能有些动静
Epps, we got Epps.
是Epps, 我们看到了Epps
...do something.
...快做些什么啊
Come man, work, work.
快点 工作 工作
All right, turn the volume up on that.
好吧 把音量转大
It's him.
是他
Can you rotate, something.
你能旋转这些东西吗
Yes, yes.
是的 很好
Okay, okay they can see us.
好了 好了 他们可以看到我们
Chicago is ground zero, you understand?
芝加哥已被夷为平地 你明白吗
- You hear us, understand?- Jesus.
-你有听到我们吗，明白吗 - 耶稣啊
The Sentinel prime is here and he has components for his space bridge.
御天敌正在这里操纵能源棒
They're on top of a building on the Chicago river.
他们在芝加哥河旁的最高大楼上
They're on the hotchess school investments.
分布传输能量
The control pillar controls everything.
控制能源棒控制一切
In the southeast cupola.
在大厦的东南圆顶上
You gotta secure the pillar. You have to shoot down the pillar.
你们得盯住能源棒，必须摧毁能源棒
Or they're going to transport Cybertron here, do you understand?
不然他们会把赛博坦传输到这里 你们明白吗
- Are you sure. - What?
- 明白吗 - 我擦
Give me the GPS on that building and on that drone.
给我大厦的GPS 并建立在靶机上
Let's go.
让我们出发
Knights ready those co-ordinates.
骑士读取坐标
Shorten the kill chain.
拉近距离连锁
Guys on the tarmac, five minutes.
他们在停机坪上 五分钟
- South east from here. - All right.
- 从这里的东南面 -好的
We need to move before the fighters spot us.
在战斗机到达前，我们必须快行动
Wait here until we scout a route ahead.
在这里等 直到我们侦察完前进路线
Let's roll.
我们出发
Ratchet, cover high.
救护车，在高处掩护
Hey, think you could use that rocket to shoot down the pillar?
嘿  可以用这火箭击落能源棒吗
We're eight blocks away.
我们有八栋建筑物远
We gotta get closer to take a shot.
我们得再接近一点去射击
Not closer, higher.
近不了了， 那就高点
We need clear line of sight.
我们需要开阔的视野
And it's across the river.
而它在河的对岸
Gonna have a hell of a time trying to sneaking up.
一定要有些时间偷偷爬上去
We only got one shot.
我们只有一发
One shot's all we need.
一发我们就足够了
We gotta be able to see around that building from the ground.
我们必须能从地面看到大厦的周围
Get NSA to send service specs for any cameras in that area.
要NSA传送这地区所有摄影机的讯息
Maybe some are working.
也许有些可以用到
Traffic lights, ATM's anything.
红绿灯 提款机 任何东西
Listen up.
听好了
You want to get back? We're going to have to wing-suit in.
你们想回来吗？ 我们将穿着飞行衣滑翔去那
It's the only way to get close.
这是唯一能接近的方式
I can't promise anyone a ride home, but if you're with me...
我不能保证每个人都能回来，但是，跟我一起的兄弟们
The world needs you now.
现在世界需要你们
I'll find my own ride home, sir.
我自己能回来，长官
Who else?
还有谁
Right here, sir.
我愿意 长官
General warn tower we're taking diversionary action to south of the city.
通告塔台，我们将采取牵制行动，飞往城市南方
We're coming north and low.
我们由北方低飞而来
You guys drop a ...
你们放下
Autobot victory, Autobot victory.
汽车人必胜！汽车人必胜！
Gotta warn you. It's scary out there, Decepticons.
得提醒你 它的可怕处在那里 霸天虎
They got my trailer, I need that flight tech.
他们拿了我的拖车我需要里面的飞行装备
Shockwave can't hunt all of us at once.
震荡波不可能同时对付我们所有人
Wreckers, we need a diversion.
雷霆小队，我们需要转移目标
- Let's get some - You got that right.
- 让我们去搞 - 你这样就对了
Listen, we're going to circle around to that glass building.
听着 我们要到那栋玻璃大厦周围
We'll get high enough to make the rocket shot.
我们抵达足够高度，才可以发射导弹
While you guys draw his fire, let's move.
你们引开他的火力 我们前进
Wait a minute.
等等
I'm not going letting you go out there without my urban-combat prototypes.
我没设置战斗模式，我哪也去不了
We gotta go, Que. Come on.
我们得走了 Q 来吧
Wait, they're great inventions for kicking ass.
等等 那可是能爆菊的伟大发明
What are these?
这些是什么
Those are boom sticks.
这些是炸弹卷
Armed in thirty seconds.
能在30秒内引爆
Grapple gloves, for climbing.
格斗手套 用来攀岩
- Move out, go on. - Move!
- 移动 快 - 移动
Go, go, go.
快走 快走 快走
Move, move! Let's go.
移动 移动 我们快走
Ah, ow, ow, ow.
啊 OW OW OW
Let's go, come on.
我们走 快点
Hey, where you going?
嘿 你要去哪里
- No, no, no. Stop, stop, stop.- Where you going?
-不 不 不  停  停  停止  -你去哪里
- Don't leave. - Never leave a bot behind.
- 不要丢下我们 - 千万别把眼前这家伙留给我们
Aw, Shockwaves coming.
啊 震荡波过来了
Go for the stairs.
到楼梯去
Epps, this way.
Epps,这边
Breaking right, breaking right.
右边断路 右边断路
Read, rolling left.
收到 旋转左边
We got another one coming around. Coming on the left side.
又一个在周围过来 从左侧
Going around on to the right side.Going around.
绕过去到右侧 绕过去
We're going to use Willis Tower for cover.
我们用威利斯大楼当掩护
Once we make altitude.
一旦我们到达预定高度
We jump.
就起跳
Hot air. Attack on one now.
热风 攻击了一个
- Man I don't think he's going to make it.- Mayday, mayday.
- 我想他不会这么做 - 求救 求救
Chopper one going down.
有一个坠落了
Come on, come on, come on.
快 快 快
Got them on target, twenty seconds.
二十秒钟到达目标
Well here we go, here we go.
我们走 我们走吧
Keep it tight.
跟紧点
Hirst, coming around.
Hirst,绕过来
All right, bolt it, bolt it, bolt it.
好的 锁住 锁住 锁住
Six o'clock.
六点钟方向
Watch out, watch out!
小心 小心
Oh, shit.
哦，见鬼
Get them out, get them out, get them out.
快出来 让他们出来 让他们出来
Now, out, out! Jump, jump, jump.
现在 出来 出来！ 跳 跳 跳
Get out, get out.
快出去 快出去
Let's fly, let's move.
让我们飞吧， 继续前进
Bail get them all down, get them all down.
让他们全部下去 让他们全部下去
Help!
救命
Get separation, track away, track away.
各自散开 分开点
More flap, more flap.
飘散点 飘散点
Check your six, Check your six.
注意六点钟方向，注意六点钟方向
He's on our ass.
他在我们屁股后面
Separate.
各自独立
Building, dead ahead.
大楼正前方
Thread the needle.
穿针引线
Pull, pull!
拉 拉
Hey come on we'll line up.
嘿 来吧 我们集结起来
This is a mother getting up here.
这是坐月子呢
-Get your fat ass over here.- I'm  coming.
- 把你的肥臀挪开 - 我来了
Set up the rocket.
设置火箭
- Come on. - We're up and status.
- 来吧 - 我们在上面就位了
Bring on bomb busters.
带上炸弹卷
20 person D bots.
20个机器人
There, the building with the Prime.
在那里 元老就在那大厦
For our brothers.
为了兄弟们
Let's make this trip worth it.
让我们不枉此行
Oh, oh God.
哦 哦 天啊
- Whoa, this building - Oh the building.
-哇 这大厦 - 哦 大厦
They're shooting at the building.
他们攻击大厦
- This is not a good idea. - What?
- 这不是个好主意 - 什么
This is not a good idea, the building's in stasis.
这不是个好主意 大厦要毁了
Just stop for a second. We don't do what we can do.
稍停一秒钟 我们不能这样做
Then it doesn't matter, we all die.
那么没关系吗 我们都死了
Right? It's your time, come on man.
对吗？ 是你的时候了，来吧哥们
I'm incapable of collapse.
我不能崩溃
I'm having a heart attack anyway.
反正我有心脏病会发作
The building is going over.
大厦要完蛋了
- Hang on.- Take cover.
- 坚持下去 - 掩护
It's okay, it's done.
没关系 停止了
Guys, look.
伙计们 你们看
- Incoming, incoming.- Everybody hide.
- 进来 进来 - 大家躲起来
Don't...move.
不要...乱动
Run!
快跑
Cover fire.
火力掩护
Shoot the glass, jump out the window.
射击玻璃 跳出窗外
Jump.
跳
Sam, I can't stop.
Sam,我停不下来
Shoot the glass.
射击玻璃
Sam.
Is everyone okay?
大家还好吗
You okay?
你还好吗
What the hell was that?
这他妈是什么鬼玩意
This Zevo thing is looking at me.
有个家伙盯着我看
What?
什么
He's even got a undulating decepticon with it.
甚至有个钻头机霸天虎
Get back.
快回来
It's coming up, the stairs are blocked.
那家伙过来了，楼梯被堵住了
Hey, how do we get out of here.
嘿 我们怎么离开这里
Hey, come on.
嘿 来吧
Oh lord, just let me get out of this alive.
我的主，请让我们脱险吧
I'll give you annuities, and get it together.
我把养老金通通给你
- Whoa!- Oh, yeah.
Move, we gotta move.
快走 我们得快逃
Why do the Decepticons always get the good shit.
为什么霸天虎总是有好东西，见鬼！
- Move. - We got leave people.
- 快走 - 我们得快闪
Give me your hand.
把你的手给我
You know, got her.
你知道，拉住她
Let's drop her to the fire escape.
把她丢到防火通道
Sam!
Whoa, we gotta move.
哇 我们得快走
Get down, move.
趴下 快走
I'm coming for you.
我来救你了
我擦了尼个玛！
Optimus!
大哥！
- Wreckers.- We're coming.
- 雷霆小队 - 我们就来
Decepticons around the world.
在各地的霸天虎
Launch the pillars.
启动能源棒
Ahh, we are so lost.
我们是如此失败
Always left out.
总是被忽略
Excellent.
妙极了
It's time to lay down the law.
是时候放弃原则
By to be the hurt now.
给他们点颜色看看
They're starting.
他们开始启动了
You see it.
你看
Get down.
小心！
Where is Sam and Carly?
Sam和Carly在哪里？
Ummm?
We can run this way.
我们可以从这里走
I give you one thing to do.
我他妈就交给你这一件事
One thing to do and you drop the ball on that.
只有一件事 你脑袋被驴踢了么
I never signed for all of this.
我可没有接到过这个
Got aliens blasting me, running around chasing me.
外星人攻击我 跑来跑去追我
I'm ducking in churches and buildings and all that kind of crap, maybe.
我躲在教堂和大厦还有这些废话
This is bullshit, I didn't sign up for this, Epps.
这是胡搞，我可没有报名参加这个 Epps
I'm trying to keep it down.
我正试着坚持下来
What a treat, you and me.
客气什么，你和我
Alone.
单独谈谈
Come on, come on. Let's run.
来吧 来吧 我们快跑
Okay, he's after me not you.
他要的是我，不是你
Wait run, run.
快跑 跑
You can't hide, boy.
你躲不掉的，臭小子
Run, move it.
跑 快走
Love it when your little insect feet,
我就是喜欢你用你那小虫子脚
...try to run!
...不停的逃
You!
你
Thought you were working for us, boy.
还以为你会为我们工作，臭小子
Sam!
Ow!
我日
My eye.
我的眼睛
My eye!
Target, Decepticon.
目标 霸天虎
Sam!
Lennox you've got to save, Sam.
伦诺克斯，你得救救他
- You've got to save him.- What is he doing?
- 你一定要救他 - 他在做什么
This better work.
这个最好能用
Ow, ow, ow. I can't see, I can't see.
噢 我看不到了！我瞎了！
Sam, take my hand.
Sam, 抓住我的手
- Cut the line, cut the line. Not that much.- I'm trying.
- 剪断线 切断线  - 我在试
The line.
线
You humans.
该死的人类
- Will you at least take it from my pocket.- What pocket?
- 至少你把它从我的口袋里拿出来 - 什么口袋
See that pocket over there.
看到那边的口袋
I got it.
我拿到了
Well hold onto to me now.
那么现在抓住我
I'll kick you.
我踢死你
Well he's dead.
他挂了么
Okay, he's going to run with the rest of the Autobots, meet us at the river.
OK,他会到河边与其余汽车人会合
All right.
好的
He sucked me in, there was nothing I could do.
他耍我 我没有什么事可以做
- Uh oh. This is a total cluster form. - Ohh.
嗯 哦 这是一个丛集排列
We gotta get across the river.
我们必须过河
You see that?
你看到了吗
She said the control pillar is in that first cupola.
她说控制能源棒在圆屋顶
Go, move. Let's move.
走 快走
Tomahawks are inbound.
战斧导弹就绪
ETA, twenty minutes.
预计20分钟到达
I'm in the traffic cameras.
我可以使用交通摄像头
Four Aubobots are captured.
他们抓了4名汽车人
Oh my God, we're helpless.
噢  天啊 ，我们竟无能为力
It was set to happen.  With those pulses getting faster it was going to happen soon.
脉冲正在加快，传输很快就会开始
No sign of Optimus.
还没有擎天柱的消息
How do we get these bridges down?
我们要如何才能把大桥降下来
Spread out, check in there.
散开  检查那里
- Epps, you're here, what are you doing? - We're looking for you man.
- Epps,你在这儿 你在干什么  - 我们正在找你
Time is wack.
时间不多了
Even worse, we can't get across the river to that dude.
更糟糕的是我们无法越过河到对岸
And the Aubobots are upstairs surrounded.
汽车人都被困在那里
Just pan the camera around, all right.
pan看看相机周围 好吗
All right pan, pan right, that's you.
好的pan 好了pan 交给你
Charging a unit to bridge control.
大桥收费站有控制系统
What are they doing there? They are just standing there.
他们怎么了，就在那杵着
Hang on, Dutch.
上去，Dutch
See if you can hack into the bridge.
看看你能不能侵入大桥系统
Sir, the seals are here.
长官 海豹队在这里
Oh it's a good day boys, what do you got?
哦，真是好日子，你们有多少人
Got ten manned navy seal element sir, and talk of charging in Tomahawks.
十个海豹突击队员，长官 战斧导弹即将到达
- How long? - Fifteen.
- 还多久  - 15分钟
Take it easy.
别紧张
Get off me.
放下我
All right, you're getting in your 40 mic mikes in your frags.
好吧 把武器切换到自动
Go for auto, the vibrations jack up their circuits.
干扰他们的电路找到弱点
Snipers, shoot for the eyes.
狙击手 瞄准他们的眼睛
All right your target is up on top of that building.
你们的目标是大厦的顶部
That cupola.
那圆顶
How doomed you are, Autobots.
你们注定失败，汽车人
You simply fail to understand.
你们根本无法理解
That the needs of the many,
少数人的需要
Out weigh the needs of the few.
必须服从多数
Activating the bridge.
启动太空桥
They have to guard something.
他们在布置防御
We're in the heart of their ship.
我们在他们的船内部
Let's give him a little ride.
让我们给他来个小操作
Ho, ho we going to screw this ship up.
活活，我们将船里的设备弄烂
It's 128K binary inscription code.
这是一个128位的二进制加密代码
It's difficult.
很复杂
But not for me, I'm in.
但难不倒我，我进去了
Bridge, down.
桥，降下
The bridge is coming down.
大桥正在下降
Someone's watching over us.
有人在帮我们
Pleasure working with you, Seymour.
很高兴与你共事，Seymour
I believe you're suppose to say.
我相信你一定想说些什么
Good job, Dutch.
干得好，Dutch
Danke schoen.
小菜一碟
Prime, they're triggering the pillars.
大哥，他们启动了能源棒
Prisoners, you're keeping prisoners?
俘虏，你在看管俘虏？
Yeeesss.
是的
You need to teach them about respect.
你必须教他们尊重
This was all business, but now it's personal.Do you understand me?
这原本是生意但现在是个人恩怨，你明白我的意思吗
I understand.
咩哈哈哈，据我所知
No prisoners.
没有战俘
Only trophies.
只有处决
B, I think they're going to kill us.
大黄蜂，我想我们这次死定了
You.
那个谁
- You're time is up.- Wait, wait, wait.
- 你的时候到了  - 等等 等等
We surrender.
我们投降
- We give...- Move it.
我们可以....- 快走
Can't we talk this out?
我们不能谈谈么
We're all a bunch of good chaps.
我们都是同类
I mean in all...unh!!!
我的意思是...
Why did you....
你为什么 ....
Goodbye my old friend.
（再见 我的老朋友）
You're mine now.
你现在是我的了
Gotta help him.
得得帮他
What?
怎么帮
What are you doing?
你在干什么
I gotta help him.
我一定要救他
You can't help him.
你没办法帮助他
Sam.
Turn around.
转过来
We, we never had it around.
（我们，我们从未拥有）
We did it brains. We did it.
我们做到了，小诸葛，我们成功了
Rip this ship apart.
把这破船弄报废
- We...we had a nice run brains, you and me. - Yeah.
-我们脑筋转的可真快，你和我 - 是啊
We're gonna die.
我们要挂了
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
哇 哇 哇
Okay baby, you are coming with us.
很好 宝贝 你是来和我们在一起的
Let's go, you guys follow that ground team, go.
快走 你们跟着这队
Move, move, move.
快走 快走 快走
Third floor, load up a 45.
这是三楼,我们得上到45楼
All right you two snipers right here.
好吧 你们两个狙击手就在这里
All right, dock up.
好了 驻守
Its up in twenty minutes.
它在二十分钟方向
Set the shot right here.
在这里设置攻击点
All right, set up.
好了 设置好
Downstairs.
在楼下
We got five targets and Shockwave right below us.
震荡波就在下面，我们有五个目标
Everybody jump.
大家跳
All right, let's go. Get ready, get ready.
好了 我们走 准备好 准备好
Go, go.
上啊，上
Snipers, take out their eyes.
狙击手，瞄准他们的眼睛打
All right, Demo team lets crank steel.
好，一队设置
Turning steel.
二队爆破
Don't fire until I tell you.
不要开火 直到我发命令
Go!
走
All right, good job.
太棒了！干得好
- Yes.  - Fire!
- 是啊  - 开火！！
- We got him.- Yeah.
-我们做到了  -是啊。
On the run.
继续跑
Autobots, attack.
汽车人，攻击
Mortar that bridge.
连接桥梁
It's our world, now.
从现在起这里是我们的世界了
Commence transport.
开始传输
My God.
天啊
Optimus!
擎天柱！
You die.
去死吧！
Nooo.
不！
Get down here, Sentinel.
下来吧，御天敌！
Optimus.
柱子！
You forget your place.
你忘了你是哪一边的么？
I bring you Cybertron.
我给你带来了赛博坦
Your  home.
你的家
And still you choose humanity.
但你仍选择和人类站在一起
You were the one who taught me freedom is everyone? right.
你不是曾经教导过我：“自由权利归众生”的么
I will retrigger that pillar.
我必须重新启动能源棒
Then you'll have to go through me.
那得先过我这关
Okay, I got to help.
OK，我要去帮忙！
- No, you don't.- Listen to me now.
不，别走  -听着
You're gonna be fine.
你会没事的
- You promised.- You're going to be fine.
你保证，你会没事的
I gotta get to that pillar.
我去能源棒那里
Guards to the pillar.
保护能源棒
We got Autobots.
我们到了，汽车人
Move, move!
快走 快
Reinforcements to me.
增援我
Decepticon six, fire at Optimus.
霸天虎们往这，干掉擎天柱
Fire, I need those tomahawks here now.
开火 我这里现在需要战斧飞弹
First wave, incoming.
第一波来了
We gotta cover for, Optimus.
我们得掩护擎天柱大哥
Decepticons, get me the pillar.
霸天虎们，快去能源棒
Restart that pillar.
重新启动能源棒
Trigger the pillars.
激活能源棒
I can't hold him.
我不能牵住他
This step I must bend.
我被压制住了
No.
不
Evac, two seconds change of clothes.
EVAC 两秒钟换装
Fourth levi, echo echo 1 4 2 5 zero,
重复、重复，14250....
- Found surface contact. - Got an ID.
收到反馈，确认ID
Target acquired.
目标确定
Dylan!
- Right.- No!
好  -不！
- Shit - Dylan.
-你妹  - Dylan.
Stop, stop.
住手，住手
No.
不
You can't do this.
你不能这么做
Okay.
行
There's only one future for me.
对我来说只有一个未来
Cybertron.
赛博坦
You are saved.
你终于得救了
At last.
在最后的时刻
Oh, have you come to surrender?
哦，你是来效忠于我的么？
- Was it all worth it? - Obviously.
这一切值得么？  -那还用说
All your work to bring Sentinel back.
你只不过是御天敌的马前卒
And now clearly he has all the power.
那老头才掌握实权
It's actually almost tragic.
实在是可悲啊
You dare lecture me, slave.
你竟敢嘲笑我？奴隶
Your decepticons finally conquering this planet.
你的霸天虎最终会占领地球
And yet their leader wasn't you.
但领袖绝不是你
It will be me, it will always be me.
他们都得听我的，一直都是
Any minute now.
再过不久
They'll be laughing.
人人都会嘲笑你了
You're Sentinels bitch.
你这个御天敌的走狗
Again!
再来
你的选择
就是个错误
Always the bravest of us.
你是我们当中最勇敢的
But you could never make the hard decisions.
但你从来不善于做出艰难决定
Now!
现在！
Our planet will survive.
我们的星球就要得救了
No.
不
We were Gods once.
一旦成功
All of us.
我们都会成为神明
But here,
但是现在
Please.
求你
They'll only be one.
那个人只会是我！
This is MY planet.
这个星球是我的！
I just saved a whole other world.
我刚才拯救了一个世界
You think you're a hero?
你以为你是英雄？
Huh, you think you're a hero.
你以为就你是英雄
No.
不
I'm just a messenger.
我只是一个传话的
It's still connected.
它仍然连接着
Watch, wait up.
看 等等
B!
大黄
Get going, get going. Let's move it.
快点跟上，快、快
Oh it's still connected.
哦，他还在运转
Lets lock it that.
我们得瞄准它
No.
不
We need a truce.
我们停战吧
All I wanted was to be back in charge.
我只想要回我的统治权
Besides...
再说
Who would you be without me?
没有我的掌控谁会承认你们？
Prime.
元老们
Time to find out.
马上你就知道了
Optimus. All I ever wanted was the survival of our race.
柱子，我唯一想要的是我们种族的生存
You must see why I had to betray you.
你需要明白我为什么背叛了你
You didn't betray me.
你没背叛我
You betrayed yourself.
你背叛了你自己
No,Optimus
不，擎天柱！
Sam.
I love you.
我爱你
You're the only thing I need in this world.
你是我的唯一，我要对你说
And I'll do anything to make it up to you, I promise.
我会为你付出一切，我保证
I'm gonna hold you to that.
我希望你此时此刻
Just never let me go.
不要离开我
Promise.
我保证
Rings.
戒指
I love this car.
我喜欢这车
But, you gotta slow down.
大黄，悠着点
You gotta slow way down.-Okay.
你得慢慢来，OK？
I'm just trying to help out.
（我只是想帮帮忙）
In any war.
战斗过后的平静
There are calms, between storms.
来自于曾经的斗争风暴
-You fought bravely.- There will be days when we loose faith.
-哥们真够劲  -或许有天我们不再有信仰
Days when our allies turn against us.
昔日的盟友变为敌人
But the day will never come.
但这天永远不会到来
That we forsake this planet.
除非我们放弃这个星球
And it's people.
和这里的人们
Do you feel cold and lost in desperation
是否你感到冰冷无助
You build up hope but failure's all you've known
你满怀希望但最终充满绝望
Let it go...
让这些不快逝去...
这就是他们所说的美好的未来么
好了，蛋定
实在是太糟糕了
把他抓起来
你们想干什么，我可是残疾人
嘿，急什么，这就走